<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>theDash Africa</title>
	<atom:link href="https://thedashafrica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://thedashafrica.com</link>
	<description>Data. Analysis. Insights.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 10:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-THEDASH-AFRICA-32x32.png</url>
	<title>theDash Africa</title>
	<link>https://thedashafrica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Rwanda, Zimbabwe sign Economic Development Agreements</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/rwanda-zimbabwe-sign-economic-development-agreements/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/rwanda-zimbabwe-sign-economic-development-agreements/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 12:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EAST AFRICAN ECONOMY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TheDash1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>On 28/09/2021, Rwanda and Zimbabwe signed agreements with Zimbabwe for the following areas of cooperation: Speaking while officially opening the conference, Hon. Biruta noted: “Rwanda and Zimbabwe...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/rwanda-zimbabwe-sign-economic-development-agreements/">Rwanda, Zimbabwe sign Economic Development Agreements</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>



<p>On 28/09/2021, Rwanda and Zimbabwe signed agreements with Zimbabwe for the following areas of cooperation:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Memorandum of Understanding on Agriculture and Livestock Development which was signed by Rwanda’s Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation, Hon. Vincent Biruta and Zimbabwe’s Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Trade, Hon. Frederick Shava.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Memorandum of Understanding on Environment and Climate Change which was signed by Rwanda’s Minister of Environment, Hon. Jeanne d’Arc Mujawamariya and Zimbabwe’s Minister of Environment, Climate, Tourism and Hospitality Industry, Hon. N. M. Ndlovu.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Memorandum of Understanding on Tourism and Business Events which was signed by the Rwanda Development Board Deputy Chief Executive Officer, Zephanie Niyonkuru and Zimbabwe’s Minister of Environment, Climate, Tourism and Hospitality Industry, Hon. N. M. Ndlovu.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Memorandum of Understanding on ICT and e-Government services which was signed by Rwanda’s Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation, Hon. Vincent Biruta and Zimbabwe’s Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Trade, Hon. Frederick Shava.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Memorandum of Understanding between Rwanda’s Private Sector Federation (PSF) and the Confederation of Zimbabwe Industries (CZI) which was signed by the PSF Chairperson, Robert Bapfakurera and the CZI Vice-President, Mucha Mkanganwi.</li>
</ul>



<p>Speaking while officially opening the conference, Hon. Biruta noted:</p>



<p>“Rwanda and Zimbabwe enjoy excellent relations that can be attested by the presence of embassies in the two countries. Indeed, as international trade contributes significantly to our economies, the organisation of such conferences is critical in ensuring business continuity and will facilitate the recovery of our economies from the economic shock of the COVID-19 pandemic.”</p>



<p>“It is a great honour for me to be invited to this important gathering. The signing of the MoUs is a major milestone for us to begin working together towards the prosperity of both our countries. We need to expeditiously come up with initiatives that propel the growth of our industries and trade. I strongly believe that through cooperation we can grow domestic industries and subsequently increase investments and trade in both countries,” said Hon. Frederick Shava, Zimbabwe’s Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Trade.</p>



<p>The Rwanda Development Board Deputy Chief Executive Officer Zephanie Niyonkuru added:</p>



<p>“The Government of Rwanda works very closely with Zimbabwe on a range of opportunities that are mutually beneficial for both our countries. These areas include trade and investments, infrastructure, energy, civil aviation among others. Rwanda and Zimbabwe share a deep commitment to excellence – and I believe these are the values that have served our working relationship in the past as they will in the future. Through our partnership and current engagements, bilateral trade could grow to desirable levels between the two countries.”</p>



<p>Speaking on behalf of Rwanda’s private sector, Robert Bapfakurera, the PSF Chairperson said:</p>



<p>“This conference is an opportunity for businesses to see how they can scale their activities in both countries and explore areas where we can share knowledge and skills for growth.”</p>



<p>Over the last two years (2019 – 2020) Zimbabwe exported goods worth US$ 15.9 million to Rwanda, while exports from Rwanda to Zimbabwe were estimated at US$ 113,607.</p>



<p>Confederation of Zimbabwe Industries (CZI) is the apex organisation for Industry in Zimbabwe and has been in existence since 1923. It is an independent, self-financed, legally constituted organisation that represents and serves interests of members in a wide array of matters affecting their viability and competitiveness.</p>



<p>While,</p>



<p>Private Sector Federation &#8211; Rwanda&#8217;s professional government organization dedicated to promoting &amp; representing the interests of the Private Sector in Rwanda.</p>



<p>This agreement comes a time when African countries are creating synergies for development and revamping the continent&#8217;s domestic economy. &nbsp;&nbsp;Rwanda, has over the years striving to expand its economic strength and such partnerships are expected to contribute greatly to its development.</p>



<p>In a recent publication, Rwanda has been ranked fourth in investment attractiveness in Africa according to a latest ranking by the Rand Merchant Bank (RMB), a leading African corporate and investment bank which is part of Firsthand Bank, one of the largest financial institutions on the continent.</p>



<p>In their 2021 release on top 10 investment attractive countries in Africa, RMB relied on indicators such as operating environments, fiscal score and development plan.&nbsp; Rwanda notably moved up the ranking to be the fourth from the ninth place last year.</p>



<p>As of the end of 2020, Rwanda had registered 172 investment projects, valued at $1.2 billion despite the Covid-19 pandemic, which slowed business activity, Rwanda Development Board statistics show.</p>



<p>Experts say that such continuous economic partnerships shall enhance the growth of Rwanda as a country and continent dominant at large and set self apart from dependence on western and eastern world countries like China, America and Europe</p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/rwanda-zimbabwe-sign-economic-development-agreements/">Rwanda, Zimbabwe sign Economic Development Agreements</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/rwanda-zimbabwe-sign-economic-development-agreements/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Investing In Uganda is a Best Choice!</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/why-investing-in-uganda-is-a-best-choice/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/why-investing-in-uganda-is-a-best-choice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 10:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TheDash1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ugandan economy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Uganda, often referred to as the pearl of Africa is bordered by South Sudan in the north, Kenya in the east, the United Republic of Tanzania in the south, Rwanda in the southwest and the Democratic Republic of Congo in the west. It is a landlocked country but perhaps with unlocked and unlimited investment opportunities.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">A potential investor considering investing in Uganda, will find a well-regulated highly liberalized economy in which all sectors are open for investment and there is a free movement of capital to and from the country.  The country has a strategic commanding base to be a regional hub for trade and investment. Uganda enjoys pivotal trade partnerships that create a viable market for business.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Unlike most other countries, in Uganda, the business operating environment allows the full repatriation of profits after the mandatory taxes have been paid, as well as 100% foreign ownership of private investments. The incentive regime is structurally embedded in the country’s tax laws making them nondiscriminatory and accessible to both domestic and foreign investment depending on the sector and level of investment.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The minimum capital investment required for a foreign investor to be eligible to invest in the country in virtually any sector, apart from those that may compromise the country’s security, is US$100,000.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Uganda’s labor is highly trainable, English speaking and the cost compares favorably in Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>WHY DO BUSINESS IN UGANDA</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Minus a wide range of opportunities and a vibrant Mushrooming economy. There are many reasons for one to invest in Uganda but most common are but not limited to the following;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Strong Incentives for Foreigners</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Uganda has very open investment incentives for foreigners, the most important include;</span></p>



<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Investment Capital Allowances</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Deductible Annual Allowances</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Duty- and Tax-free import of plant and machinery</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">First arrival privileges for personal effects and motor vehicles</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Export zones</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">No restriction to 100% ownership of investments</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">No barriers to remittances of dividends</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Fully convertible Currency</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Capital account transactions and exchange market fully liberalized</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">No restrictions on capital transfers</span></li>
</ul>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Ownership in Companies</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">There are no restrictions on the equity share that foreign nationals may hold in a locally incorporated company and no rules or regulations restricting joint ventures between Ugandan and foreign investors.  These issues are subject to mutual agreement between the partners.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Performance Requirements</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Foreign investors are subject to performance obligations regarding the size of investment, staff training and local employment, local procurement and environmental protection.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Labor issues</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Uganda has a large quantity of both skilled and non-skilled, professional and technical English-speaking workers. On the World Banks Doing Business Survey 2007, Uganda ranks first among all sub-Saharan countries in terms of ease of hiring. The country does not have a history of labor disputes or strikes. Many existing investors see the existing labor regulations as unproblematic and in much favor of the investors for better growth.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Investment Protection</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The investment code protects licensed investors. Uganda has signed various bilateral and multilateral agreements.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Fiscal incentives for foreign investors in Uganda</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Uganda&#8217;s fiscal incentive package provides for generous capital recovery terms, particularly for investors whose projects entail significant investment in plant and machinery and whose investments are medium/long term.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Investment restrictions and sectors not entitled to investment incentives</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The investment code allows foreigners to invest in all activities except for those which compromise national security, or which require the ownership of land.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Legality of Company formation</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In Uganda, you can operate business under two categories 1) as a foreign company or 2) Local company. Foreign companies are companies incorporated outside Uganda but extending their business into Uganda. Local company or business is one that is incorporated and registered in Uganda regardless of the shareholders origin. It was now made easy in a way that even one person(shareholder) can register a limited liability company unlike in the past when two or more shareholders were needed to form a company</span></p>



<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>To register a local or foreign company or business in Uganda is easy and cheap.  If you are not well versed with the country dynamic and professional tasks required, just get a consultant or firm like <a href="http://www.nbkpremier.com">NBK-Premier Solutions Ltd</a>, then the process can take you even no hustle.    Call/WhatsApp: +256704597816.</strong></span></p>
</blockquote>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>About Land</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The right to all land is vested in the citizens of Uganda.  Foreign investors may only own land in a joint venture with a majority local shareholder. Leasing is an option for all foreign investors, for terms anywhere from five to 99 years from private owners, municipal councils and other public agencies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">LAND IS AVAILABLE IN THREE CATEGORIES:</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Public land:  Both local and foreigners may lease public land, which is available through municipal councils and District Land Commissions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Leased land: Available from Buganda Land Board and other landlords</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Freehold: Available from private individuals for sale or contractual lease.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Paying Taxes</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Income tax is at 30% of net income (after all business expense and deductions) VAT is at 18% and Withholding tax for purchases at 6%.  Dividend and capital payments are allowed subject to the tax laws of Uganda. Dividends are subjected to withholding (rate for residents and non-residents is 15%). With the approval of the Bank of Uganda, dividends can be remitted to non-resident shareholders. Capital gains on business assets are subject to a tax rate or 30%.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Sample Sectors.</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Agriculture and Agro processing.</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Post harvesting equipment, such as packaging and food processing facilities. Opportunities to invest in Small and Medium Enterprises in the agriculture sector exist in:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Farming and Agri business </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Packaging of fruits and vegetables</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Investment in cold storage facilities at collecting point</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Laboratory testing services, material, equipment</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Production of sun-dried products</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Manufacturing</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Opportunities exist in plenty when it come to manufacturing. Uganda is just moving and opening up for manufacturing of various items from the traditional products and packaging.  Main sectors for manufacturing based Small and Medium Enterprises in Uganda are: Foods and beverages, textiles and garments, wood crafts, leather products, printing and graphics products, Chemical and Pharmaceuticals, Handcrafts, Building materials and ceramics, just to name but a few.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Food and Beverages</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Uganda has a competitive advantage in farming and processing of several foods and beverages. Possible investment opportunities are in:</span></p>



<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Planting and processing of coffee </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Extraction of vegetable and essential oils </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Packaging of beans and other vegetables for export </span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Etc.</span></li>
</ul>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Building materials</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Investment opportunities are available in:</span></p>
<p>Manufacture of pre-fabricated concrete systems</p>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Establishment of mini-cement factories</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Exploitation of non-metallic minerals to provide floor/wall tiles, cement, glass, etc</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Services</strong></span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Investment opportunities in the services sector range from financial services, tourism and information technology/electronics sector, hospitality, engineering, consultancies, technical works, etc.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">There are over 260 investment opportunities in Uganda and choosing the best for you requires a quick assessment of your needs so as better recommendations are done. In case you may be reading this article at your desirous moment to venture into Ugandan business and unaware of where to start, then consultants like:  <a href="http://www.nbkpremier.com">NBK PREMIER SOLUTIONS</a> will guide you.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Uganda, will never disappoint when it comes to investments.</span></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/why-investing-in-uganda-is-a-best-choice/">Why Investing In Uganda is a Best Choice!</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/why-investing-in-uganda-is-a-best-choice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uganda, TotalEnergies &#038; CNOOC Sign a $10 billion Mega Oil Deal</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/uganda-totalenergies-cnooc-sign-a-10-billion-mega-oil-deal/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/uganda-totalenergies-cnooc-sign-a-10-billion-mega-oil-deal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 09:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oli and Gas in Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ugandan economy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Uganda discovered crude oil reserves in the western part of the country along the border with the Democratic Republic of Congo in 2006, but production was several times flunked by disagreements between the government and oil firms over tax and development strategy, and a lack of infrastructure which some players also defined as economic hindering politics that slowed down some progress making many companies like Tullow Oil sell off and leave.  To many it was a dream not to come true.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It was a resilient journey and behold, on the 1<sup>st</sup> Feb, 2022, <a href="https://corporate.totalenergies.ug/">TotalEnergies</a> and  its partner <a href="https://cnoocinternational.com/en/operations/middle-east-and-africa/uganda">China National Offshore Oil Corporation (CNOOC)</a>  reached a deal with Ugandan government (in partnership with Tanzania) to invest more than $10 billion in developing crude oil production in Uganda, using Tanzania as the pipeline to the coast.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The signing of the Final Investment Decision (FID) agreement will for the first time see Uganda drill and produce its first barrel of oil and put out a variety of oil and gas production infrastructures.  The development of oil fields, processing facilities and a pipeline network in Uganda, plus an export pipeline through Tanzania to carry landlocked Uganda&#8217;s crude to a port on the Indian Ocean were already planned awaiting this historical signing of the FID to start operations.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">According to Total Energies, this is a commitment to invest over $10 billion in the project. Given the magnitude of the project, over 160,000 jobs are expected to be created according to projections form government.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In line with TotalEnergies goal to reinvent energy by providing green and renewable energy solutions, the company has also signed a memorandum of understanding with Uganda to collaborate on &#8220;large scale renewable energy development projects, this will enable TotalEnergies, develop solar, wind, geothermal and other renewable technology power projects with a combined installed electricity output capacity of 1 gigawatt by 2030.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">CNOOC and TotalEnergies shall handle the Tilenga and Kingfisher upstream oil projects in Uganda and the construction of the East African Crude Oil Pipeline (EACOP) in Uganda and Tanzania. The Tilenga project shall be operated by TotalEnergies and the Kingfisher project shall be operated by CNOOC and all are expected to start producing oil in 2025 and to reach a cumulative plateau production of 230,000 barrels per day.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The upstream shall be shared by TotalEnergies (56.67%), CNOOC (28.33%) and UNOC (15%). Production from the oil fields in Uganda will be transported to the port of Tanga in Tanzania through the EACOP cross-border pipeline, whose shareholders are TotalEnergies (62%), UNOC (15%), TPDC (15%) and CNOOC (8%).   Uganda National Oil Company is representing the interests of the government of Uganda. Tanzania also has a stake in the pipeline company through the Tanzania Petroleum Development Corporation (TPDC)</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The length of the pipeline shall be 1,440-kilometr, planned for completion in 36 months’ time and when complete, will transport crude oil from Hoima Western Uganda to the Tanzanian Port of Tanga that connects to the Indian Ocean.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Out of the whole expected investment to be between USD 10-15 billion will leave at least 4.2 billion of the expenses going to Ugandans and Ugandan companies under the local content policy, according to projections in the contact frameworks</span>.</p>



<p></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Investment deal will further facilitate Uganda’s GDP growth by 22 per cent and also unlock over 160,000 jobs where over 57 per cent will be given to Ugandans, attracting 4.8 billion dollars (about 16.8 trillion Uganda shillings).</span></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/uganda-totalenergies-cnooc-sign-a-10-billion-mega-oil-deal/">Uganda, TotalEnergies & CNOOC Sign a $10 billion Mega Oil Deal</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/03/uganda-totalenergies-cnooc-sign-a-10-billion-mega-oil-deal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Understanding the UAE&#8217;s Fourth Industrial Revolution (4IR) Strategy</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/02/inside-the-uaes-fourth-industrial-revolution-4ir-strategy/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/02/inside-the-uaes-fourth-industrial-revolution-4ir-strategy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 09:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology and Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UAE ECONOMY]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">For starters that could be so new to this 4IR: </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><em><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Fourth Industrial Revolution (4IR) is a technological revolution that merges the physical, digital and biological technologies in order to deliver unprecedented products and services in new and emerging sectors.</span></em></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">UAE’s growth in recent years has been based on strategic plans and buoyant leaders. These leaders have transformed the national economy basin on the digital and technical models that has contributed to creating real opportunities for foreign and direct investments, opportunities and an extraordinary country branding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The buoyant leaders are creating a digital economy implemented through the adoption of the UAE Strategy for the Fourth Industrial Revolution aiming at enhancing economic security.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In September 2017, the leaders’ decision allowed the UAE Government to launch the UAE Strategy for the Fourth Industrial Revolution (4IR) during the Government’s Annual Meetings. The UAE Strategy is aimed to strengthen the UAE’s position as a global hub for the 4IR and to increase its contribution to the national economy by means of advancing innovation and future technologies</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It also aims to position the UAE as a global model in adopting leading-edge technologies to serve society and achieve happiness and sustainability.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 18pt;">Vision</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The vision of the UAE’s 4IR Strategy is to become a leading global hub and an open lab for the Fourth Industrial Revolution’s applications.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 18pt;">The Dream Mission</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The UAE&#8217;s big dream mission is to become a hub and the world’s first open lab for experimenting and adopting the Fourth Industrial Revolution’s technologies.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 18pt;">First of its Kind, globally</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The UAE&#8217;s Fourth Industrial Revolution Strategy, the first of its kind globally, was designed to provide a practical framework for policy makers and support national efforts in adopting advanced technologies and transforming future challenges into opportunities that better serve the country.  The Fourth Industrial Revolution marked a significant and impactful milestone in the future of the United Arab Emirates offering unprecedented opportunities and several challenges that should be addressed and utilized efficiently.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 18pt;">Aims of the strategy </span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The strategy aims to:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Achieve future security of water and food supply by using bioengineering sciences and advanced renewable energy technologies</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Enhance economic security by adopting digital economy and block-chain technologies in financial transactions and service</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Optimize the utilization of satellite data in planning future cities</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Develop advanced defense industries by developing national industries in the field of robotics and autonomous vehicle technologies.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The strategy further outlines the path to achieve the future experience of government services by providing intelligent and interactive government services around the clock to achieve customer happiness and to position the UAE as a model for interactive cities using artificial intelligence to achieve sustainability.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The strategy focuses on a number of key fields. Some of them are innovative education, artificial intelligence, intelligent genomic medicine and robotic healthcare.</span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Innovative education will provide a smart and enhanced learning experience to develop advanced technologies such as science, nanotechnology and artificial intelligence.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The adoption of intelligent and personal genomic medicine will lead to personalized medical technologies, improved health care levels and boost the UAE’s position as a global center for healthcare.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The adoption of robotic healthcare and research in nanotechnology will facilitate the application of telemedicine and introduce cutting-edge medical solutions such as wearable and implantable technologies.</span></li>
</ol>
<h1><span style="font-size: 18pt;">Standing on 6 Key Pillars</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-2404 alignright" src="http://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/uae-4ir-300x227.png" alt="" width="415" height="314" srcset="https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/uae-4ir-300x227.png 300w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/uae-4ir.png 672w" sizes="(max-width: 415px) 100vw, 415px" />The Fourth Industrial Revolution (4IR) Strategy of the UAE comprises 6 pillars.</span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Human of the future</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Security of the future</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Experience of the future</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Productivity of the future</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Frontiers of the future</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Foundations of the future.</span></li>
</ol>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: 18pt;">Strategic areas of each Pillar</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Below are the strategic areas under each of the pillars:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong> &#8216;<span style="font-size: 18pt;">The Human of the future’</span></strong></span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Augmented Learning &#8211;</strong> </span>develop a leading dynamic and intelligent augmented learning experience to improve education outcomes and meet the new requirements of the Fourth Industrial Revolution to focus on advanced sciences and technologies (e.g., bioengineering, Nano-technology and Artificial Intelligence).</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Personalized Medicine </strong></span>&#8211; drive the development of a hyper-personalized, intelligent genomics hub to dramatically improve the population’s health and promote genomic medical tourism.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Robo-Care</strong> </span>&#8211; harness clinical cobots and nanobots to augment the UAE’s healthcare capabilities and provide remote robotic medical services inside the UAE and abroad.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Connected Care &#8211; </strong></span>drive the advancement and adoption of Connected Care in the UAE to provide intelligent healthcare interventions through wearable and implantable technologies.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong> ‘The Security of the future’</strong></span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">Food and Water Security</span> </strong>&#8211; develop a sustainable food and water ecosystem by leveraging bioengineering, advanced sciences and technologies as well as renewable energy.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Economic Security &#8211;</strong></span> adopt digital economy technologies (e.g. blockchain) to future-proof the UAE’s financial ecosystem.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Space Data</strong> </span>&#8211; employing space data and technologies to make intelligent and strategic decisions.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">Advanced Defense Manufacturing &#8211;</span></strong> augment the UAE’s advanced defence manufacturing capabilities with collaborative robots and cognitive technologies to ensure a safe and protected future.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong> <span style="font-size: 14pt;">‘The Experience of the future’</span></strong></span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Intelligent Government Services</strong> &#8211;</span> deliver the world’s best intelligent, seamless and citizen-centric government services that boosts the happiness and wellbeing of customers.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Intelligent Consumer Experience &#8211;</strong></span> deliver an intelligent, hyper-personalized retail and hospitality experience to make the UAE the world’s leading destination for consumers.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">Intelligent Cities &#8211;</span> </strong>become the world’s powerhouse for intelligent cities and premises to improve environmental sustainability and enhance the human lifestyle.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">NextGen Mobility &#8211;</span> </strong>become the world’s open lab for autonomous and sustainable mobility to lead the innovations in transportation.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong> ‘The Productivity of the future’</strong></span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">Open Additive Manufacturing &#8211;</span></strong> focus on designing and programming 3-D additive design and manufacturing technologies to unlock the competitive potential of the UAE economy and entrepreneurs globally.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">3D Printed Construction &#8211;</span></strong> become the world’s centre of excellence in 3D printed and robotic construction to deliver sustainable value for the economy.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">Intelligent Grids &#8211;</span> </strong>pioneer future grids to enable decentralized energy generation, sustainable consumption, and intelligent asset management.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">Intelligent Supply Chains &#8211;</span></strong> develop the world’s next generation intelligent terminals and logistics ecosystem to maximize productivity in a sustainable manner.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>‘The Frontiers of the future’</strong></span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">Commercialization of Space</span> &#8211;</strong> serve as a global hub for ambitious space players and support space entrepreneurship to accelerate the accessibility to commercialization of space.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Cognitive Human Enhancement</strong> &#8211;</span> support national research and application efforts in national universities and specialized centres in the field of brain, neuro science and human enhancement in collaboration with global leaders in the field.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>‘The Foundations of the future’</strong></span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Future Talent</strong> </span>&#8211; prepare a national talent pool and entrepreneurs for the Fourth Industrial Revolution and equip them with the required knowledge and skills in advanced science and technology through an applied educational system focused on innovation and entrepreneurship in the high priority sectors.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #008000;">Integrated cyber secured data Environment</span> &#8211; </strong>build an integrated cyber-secured big data environment equipped with intelligent connectivity and develop the necessary protocols to protect it.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>4IR Policies &amp; Regulations</strong> </span>&#8211; develop conducive and innovative policies and regulations that cover the Fourth Industrial Revolution’s themes and applications to ensure maintaining the privacy and well-being of citizens.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>4IR Values and Ethics</strong> &#8211;</span> cultivate steadfast values and ethics in the future generations to ensure making the optimal use of the Fourth Industrial Revolution and steadily facing its challenges.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Global 4IR Hub &#8211;</strong> </span>create a global 4IR hub to promote a competitive national economy based on knowledge, innovation and the 4IR technologies and applications.</span></li>
</ol>
<h1><span style="font-size: 18pt;">What UAE Leaders Say About the 4IR Strategy </span></h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>We should provide ourselves with modern sciences and far-reaching knowledge. We should seek knowledge with true enthusiasm and honest desire to be able to practice all kinds of constructive work. That will enable the UAE to achieve a significant civilizational transformation in the third millennium.</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">&#8211; His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The President of the United Arab Emirates</span></p>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>&#8220;It is a long journey full of challenges, which requires combined efforts and national energies. The UAE is relying on its citizens to continue this journey, and it will provide them with the necessary tools and working mechanisms to adopt future technologies and advanced sciences, as well as everything required to successfully go through this experience and achieve it, through a clear path towards the future.   We started this when we launched the Fourth Industrial Revolution Strategy, which is a new era of government work, and we are currently looking forward to developing it and maintaining its sustainability. We are aware that this requires developing the skills of our government working team, and we are expecting all its members to intensify their efforts to achieve the required progress for the government of the future,&#8221;</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"> &#8211; His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Vice President, Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai</span></p>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>&#8220;Our reliance upon knowledge and scientific thinking to achieve total development is the only way to bring our nation ahead to the stage of qualitative, non-oil production&#8221;.</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">&#8211; His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi and Deputy Supreme Commander of the UAE Armed Forces</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/02/inside-the-uaes-fourth-industrial-revolution-4ir-strategy/">Understanding the UAE’s Fourth Industrial Revolution (4IR) Strategy</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/02/inside-the-uaes-fourth-industrial-revolution-4ir-strategy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inside UAE’s AED 300 Billion 2031 industrial strategy</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/inside-uaes-aed-300-billion-2031-industrial-strategy/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/inside-uaes-aed-300-billion-2031-industrial-strategy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retail and Manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UAE ECONOMY]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE is diversifying its economy and expanding its industrial base to reduce reliance on imports of industrial inputs and cut dependence on global supply chains after...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/inside-uaes-aed-300-billion-2031-industrial-strategy/">Inside UAE’s AED 300 Billion 2031 industrial strategy</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">UAE is undoubtedly the Arab world’s second-largest economy and this is not by accident but decisions and strategies their leaders make. One of the recent outstanding one being the <strong><a href="https://u.ae/en/about-the-uae/strategies-initiatives-and-awards/federal-governments-strategies-and-plans/the-uae-industrial-strategy">&#8220;Operation 300 bn&#8221;</a></strong>. It is a national industrial strategy aimed at raising the manufacturing sector’s contribution from Dh133 to Dh300 billion by 2031.  The strategy was named Operation 300bn because of its ultimate goal of raising the industrial sector’s contribution to the GDP from AED 133 billion to AED 300 billion by 2031.</span></p>



<h2><strong>What Goal?</strong></h2>



<p>&nbsp;<span style="font-size: 14pt;">Launched by His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of UAE and Ruler of Dubai, in March 2021, the technical goal of the mega strategy was to support the setting up of 13,500 industrial companies and &nbsp;help increase spending on research and development in the industrial sector from Dh21 billion to Dh57 billion.</span></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>The UAE is diversifying its economy and expanding its industrial base to reduce reliance on imports of industrial inputs and cut dependence on global supply chains after the pandemic that uprooted world trade the last two years.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>T<span style="font-size: 14pt;">he strategy is further targeted to increase the manufacturing sector&#8217;s contribution to the country&#8217;s economic output, boost local production, increase purchase and spending towards local products and local suppliers, as well as promoting investment in research and development and incentivizing adoption of advanced local made technology in the UAE.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It is the largest and most comprehensive plan for developing the UAE’s industrial sector and enhancing its role in stimulating the national economy.&nbsp;</span></p>



<h2><strong>The vision</strong></h2>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The strategy stems from an integrated vision of the ministry to:</span></p>



<ol type="1">
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Develop the UAE’s industrial sector</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Increase its in-country value (ICV)</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Establish the UAE as a global hub for future industries</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Build the reputation of the UAE’s industrial products through the promotion of exports to global markets and &#8211;</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Create quality job opportunities in the industrial sector.</span></li>
</ol>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The strategy further seeks efficiency and sustainability of the production cycles and supply chains by driving research and development (R&amp;D), establishing a comprehensive system of specifications and standards to create an integrated quality infrastructure for the industrial sector, as well as implementing sustainable industrial policies that reduce resource consumption, and support climate action and carbon neutrality efforts.</span></p>



<h2><strong>6 Pillar Objectives</strong></h2>



<p>The strategy is built on 6 major objectives:</p>



<ol type="1">
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">To create a relevant and attractive business environment for local and international investors in the industrial sector</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">To support the growth of national industries and enhance their global competitiveness</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">To stimulate innovation by accelerating advanced technology adoption across the industrial value chain to upgrade systems and solutions, boost productivity and forge competitive advantages in new areas</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">To build on the solid industrial foundations that have helped fortify the UAE’s position as a global leader in industries of the future</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">to cultivate a culture of innovation in the ministry</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">To provide a comprehensive array of administrative services in accordance with the highest</span> standards of quality, efficiency and transparency.</li>
</ol>



<h2>&nbsp;<strong>17 Supporting Initiatives</strong></h2>



<p>The strategy is built on the following 17 initiatives:</p>



<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Establishing an integrated R&amp;D ecosystem</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Positioning the UAE as a pioneering global destination for technology and innovation</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Developing an advanced technology roadmap that drives innovation</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Establishing standards and metrology that support advanced technology adoption</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Catalyzing the adoption of the 4IR technology to boost the productivity of anchor industries</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Launching an ICV program</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Promoting the ‘Made in the Emirates’ brand and national products</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Developing an integrated quality infrastructure</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Negotiating reciprocal trade agreements and work to control the classification system of traded products for export and import</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Modernizing the industrial law</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Offering attractive energy and gas tariffs to eligible sectors</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Launching a framework for partnerships with industrial sectors to develop standards and metrology</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Providing flexible financing at competitive costs for priority sectors</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Establishing a digital ministry by 2022</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Advancing digital transformation to simplify registration, licensing and fee procedures</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Building a data management platform</span>.</li>
</ul>



<h2><strong>&nbsp;11 vital sectors</strong></h2>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In implementation of the strategy, the allied ministry is focusing on the following 11 vital industrial sectors:</span></p>



<p>Stimulating growth.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Food, beverage and</li>



<li>Agricultural technology</li>



<li>Pharmaceuticals</li>



<li>Electrical equipment and electronics</li>
</ul>



<p>Advanced manufacturing.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Increasing productivity, boosting economic contribution and creating job opportunities</li>



<li>Petrochemicals and chemical products</li>



<li>Rubber and plastics</li>



<li>Machinery and equipment</li>
</ul>



<p>Creating a conducive environment for developing industries of the future</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Hydrogen</li>



<li>Medical technology</li>



<li>Space technology.</li>
</ul>



<h2><strong>A strong Support Pillar</strong></h2>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This strategy and all its structure is being implemented with support of the Emirates Development Bank (EDB).  Under the strategy, the bank allocated in total a portfolio of AED 30 billion to support priority industrial sectors over a period of initial five years. The bank is committed to financing 13,500 SMEs that are estimated to creating 25,000 jobs in the following sectors:</span></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Manufacturing: petrochemicals, plastics, heavy industries, machinery, electrical appliances and renewable energy equipment</li>



<li>Infrastructure: energy, transportation, communications and digital infrastructure</li>



<li>Technology: software, IT, storage devices, peripherals, renewable energy technology and education technology</li>



<li>Healthcare: pharmaceuticals, biotechnology, medical equipment and hospital services</li>



<li>Food security: agriculture, livestock, aquaculture and water desalination.</li>
</ul>



<h2><strong>National goals inline with  International SDGs</strong></h2>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The objectives of Operation 300bn align with the UAE’s commitments to global climate action as well as the Sustainable Development Goals 2030. Objectives include safeguarding public health, advancing sustainable economic growth, deploying clean energy solutions, driving industrial innovation and promoting responsible consumption and production.</span></p>



<p>T<span style="font-size: 14pt;">o achieve these priorities, the UAE Cabinet adopted the<strong> <a href="https://u.ae/en/about-the-uae/strategies-initiatives-and-awards/federal-governments-strategies-and-plans/uae-circular-economy-policy">Circular Economy Policy 2021-2031</a></strong>,  a comprehensive framework that guides the country’s efforts to ensure sustainable and efficient use of resources with the aim of preserving them for future generations.</span></p>



<h2>A strategy in line with the National 4IR Plan</h2>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">All key initiatives within Operation 300bn are positioned to encouraging the development and adoption of <strong><a href="https://u.ae/en/about-the-uae/strategies-initiatives-and-awards/federal-governments-strategies-and-plans/the-uae-strategy-for-the-fourth-industrial-revolution">Fourth Industrial Revolution (4IR)</a></strong> applications and advanced technologies to generate significant economic returns, reduce the environmental footprint of the industrial sector and boost its competitiveness.</span></p>



<p>INFORMATION SOURCE &amp; VALIDITY:  <a href="https://u.ae/en">UAE Government Portal</a></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/inside-uaes-aed-300-billion-2031-industrial-strategy/">Inside UAE’s AED 300 Billion 2031 industrial strategy</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/inside-uaes-aed-300-billion-2031-industrial-strategy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Future-readiness &#8211; 8 Lessons Entrepreneurs must keep at Heart.</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/future-readiness-8-lessons-entrepreneurs-must-keep-at-heart/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/future-readiness-8-lessons-entrepreneurs-must-keep-at-heart/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 05:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retail and Manufacturing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Traditional buying will remain but Technology, e-commerce and digitization shall keep essential too DON&#8217;T MISS OUT MORE of LIGHT-SPEED Insights! from my platform.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/future-readiness-8-lessons-entrepreneurs-must-keep-at-heart/">Future-readiness – 8 Lessons Entrepreneurs must keep at Heart.</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Entrepreneurs have always (and will always) known better, that learning from crisis, mistakes and experiences is the best way to invent the future. Every entrepreneur knows that resilience is essential to turn adversity into success, manage crises and grow businesses.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">2020 and 2021 proved to everyone that having the traits, skills and resources to successfully adapt to changes in the business landscape is not just helpful – it is essential. This is what I call “future-readiness” – and it is now! It is essential. It is a critical element of today&#8217;s economic survival.  </span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">With the disruption caused by COVID-19 universal pandemic, most MSMEs that have survived have been a result of lessons learnt swiftly and these shall always be etched to their strategy for growth. As a consultant and entrepreneur that exists to help business and investments succeed, I recently sat down and captured these 8 ways that shall make enterprises thrive at every stage of their journey and be ready to wither future challenges and form deeper connections thus getting future-readiness.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">With no explanation we all know the waves that have been sweeping off the globe. The pandemic created a very ugly disruption for the global and local everything.  Everyone, everything was directly or indirectly disrupted by the pandemic. Changes were to inevitably come. Nothing remained the same.</span>   </p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Amidst all, one thing was for sure – We were to make a comeback, but, the comeback was not another old folk play of rinsing the same. It was a reimagined comeback. </span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Firms whether big or small that thrived or are thriving are those that took initiative to revise the way to do business. This revision was relative to each industry and business.  But few things remained evident to make meaning for now and the future. I explored a few nuggets briefly below! </span></p>



<h1><strong>The rise of Hybrid Shopping</strong></h1>



<p><strong>Traditional buying will remain but Technology, e-commerce and digitization shall keep essential too</strong></p>



<figure id="attachment_2376" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2376" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-2376 size-medium" src="http://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/hybrid-shoopoing-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/hybrid-shoopoing-300x300.jpg 300w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/hybrid-shoopoing-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/hybrid-shoopoing-150x150.jpg 150w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/hybrid-shoopoing-768x768.jpg 768w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/hybrid-shoopoing.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2376" class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy Photo</figcaption></figure>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Digitization, Digitalization!  You must have heard that for long. Simply put, it means using technology to optimize the ways of doing business and drive growth, convenience and reduced costs.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The only reason for digitization to trend is that it opens the door of opportunities, possibilities and revenue streams, enabling new ways and approaches of service delivery, communication, creation of new products and services, etc.  It increases the <strong>speed of</strong> response to changes in demand in the market. It generates a competitive advantage for the company by being able to enhance the quality of the products and services and most importantly gives inclusive access to information, services and lifestyles.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The physical interaction, physical meetings and instore shopping will remain but it will be guided by e-commerce, technology and digital communications – digitization.   Inevitably digitalization is the way we shop and do business of late. The success of most businesses post Covid19 shall be determined by how flexible they adapt to digital and technological trends.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Movements and crowding is likely to remain regulated for an additional time for some good time and even if your business had the essential provision to pull on site crowds as clients, the regulatory restrictions and myths shall cost you a little high, more so you will need marketing and communication with your crowds &#8211; which is digital. </span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">So, what happens?  Even if you are running a retail store, the days of delivering paper quotations and then deliver items physically seem to be going, more than ever small and big business shall get to digital means for most of the services.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The businesses whose policy is come to shop, store or office are likely to lose out big. More than ever, phone call orders, digital transactions, communication and allied flexibility is going to be a mandatory aspect for any succeeding business.  Many trends ranging from CRM Systems, Cashless Payment, digital invoicing/receipting, Cyber/digital security, data collection and communication systems, etc are going to be the new normal for a business to succeed regardless of size.</span></p>



<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>So pause and ask; what digital trends can I apply to my business, what e-commerce opportunities can I grab and what technological tools can I use to keep relevant?</em></span></p>
</blockquote>



<h1>Data collection and Management</h1>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I work with dozens of small and medium enterprises as a consultant. Most SMALL businesses have no single effective data collection and management systems. This is going to change. Having data about your business transactions and customers is going to be a game changer in many ways, from marketing, to retention, to seeking financing. The client who got all data well managed has many chances to turn things around than the traditional wait business person.</span></p>



<h1>Flexibility in Employment</h1>



<figure id="attachment_2381" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2381" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-2381" src="http://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/remote-work-300x170.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="170" srcset="https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/remote-work-300x170.jpg 300w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/remote-work-768x435.jpg 768w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/remote-work.jpg 891w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2381" class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><em>Credit: Uplers &#8211; remote work</em></span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">When the going gets tough, the tough get going, says an old adage. Employment is going to change too. From limited money to pay salaries and need for more intangible resources, to limited access of work places and less physical interactions, the successful entrepreneur must revise and understand a new way to have partners and teams that deliver.  Could be there some workforce that you can outsource to remote freelancers who don’t require big payments and regulatory benefits and contractual obligations? Those that shall execute per tasks other than idly being at work place consuming services and expanding bills?</span></p>



<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Could many employees get an option to work from home part timely or get paid per task and allow you to cut some expenses?</span></p>
</blockquote>



<h1>Security and hygiene</h1>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">More than ever, for the entrepreneur to succeed post Covid-19 must be a security conscious one. As crisis increase, crimes too are going to increase and corrupt behaviors and to succeed in this there shall be need to secure tangible and intangible properties, data, systems, ideas, etc.   More than ever the careless entrepreneur shall lose out. The way you keep records, confidential documents, discussions, property, equipment, etc. depending on your industry.  Is your office and data protected from data loss and hackers since 50 % employees work from home under unmonitored network sources and IP addresses? Digital and cyber security are going to be key drivers of what next.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Getting to hygiene, more than ever disorganized and unhygienic packaging, processing, work force, work places and etc, shall be seen as losers in the coming season. The whole crisis resonates on hygiene practices and people especially those dealing in food and human consumption services more than ever are to adapt to high standard hygiene services else they lose.</span></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>What hygiene solutions are required at your work place and delivery models of products or services and what are you doing about it?</em></span></p>
</blockquote>



<h1>Professional Support Services</h1>



<p> </p>
<figure id="attachment_2226" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-2226" src="http://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-photo-2422278-300x225.jpeg" alt="professional at work" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-photo-2422278-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-photo-2422278-768x575.jpeg 768w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-photo-2422278.jpeg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2226" class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em>man in suit smiling</em></span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Whereas everyone is smart in business (which we tend to be as entrepreneurs) but you cannot tackle all business matters personally and hiring a full time professional for such tasks that come once in a while is not a good move, so engaging an outside expert can be an extra measure to ensure business receive proper attention for growth.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It also can be useful to have a third-party’s perspective on matters that require objectivity, or an “extra set of eyes” to verify that no mistakes made in a critical process and the business growth is on an ascending curve other than gambling.  Before it was ok to try and fail and try again until you figure things out but now it will be expensive to be a try-and-see person in such a delicate situation of low resources and jaw biting competition.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">From business development strategies, to compliance, contracts and tender processes, legal suits, name it all, you need an external support consultant or professional. Better to spend 10m shillings on consultancy services and 10m shillings on business set up and development than putting all 20m to risk and burn while drifting</span>. </p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Business support services like consultancy, accountancy, legal, technological etc are going to be key drivers of any business regardless of size and industry.   Unarguably, we all know that every new development brings with it changing risks and it becomes good to prevent the risk than curing it. External support service makes this possible.</span></p>



<h1>Communication and negotiation</h1>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">More than ever for businesses to thrive they must learn the art of communication and negotiation, short of that, few will survive. In this hybrid setting of things that is trending, how we interact both directly and indirectly matters, from text communications, audio visual, direct interaction, etc. Business communication can be direct verbal, text or psychological like the way we position, structure offices and stores, websites, etc.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Negotiation is a discussion or systems built to take into account everybody’s needs and interests so that no one is at loss. Good negotiations are very important as they contribute much to business success and build better relations.   From your marketing materials to the website and phone calls you make to the setup of an office and systems, this must be kept in mind and positioned well.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Communication and negotiation is not only about talk but also in overall branding processes. Ever walked to an office and felt intimidated to ask a question or discount just because of their system structure or access set up? </span></p>



<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Ever went to the bank that its set up was not good to strike good conversation away from the formal inquiries, the list is endless. This is too integral in overall business processes.</strong></span></p>
</blockquote>



<h1>Systems &amp; Standards Certifications</h1>



<figure id="attachment_2377" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2377" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-2377" src="http://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/standards-300x150.png" alt="" width="300" height="150" srcset="https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/standards-300x150.png 300w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/standards.png 318w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2377" class="wp-caption-text"><em><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Credit: allthingsstunning</span></em></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">From documentation, policies and procedures, quality control, financial records, customer interactions, transactions, delivery models, plans, business contacts, employee details, regulatory requirements and so on, business require certain standards and systems fully certified to beat competition and have smooth productive operations. </span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Without effective systems you cannot manage to thrive effectively. Systems and standards are an essential part of the business and post Coid-19 it will not only be essential but integral to manage and build a successful business.  </span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">System certifications and standards are used by both small and big businesses to demonstrate their ability to consistently provide products and services that meet customer and regulatory requirements under acceptable disciplines. As people are getting cautious and skeptical of what they buy, the entrepreneur with no standards and certifications will not make massive sales and deals. Adoption of both micro and mega local &amp; internationally recognized management systems and standards is a great deal in the coming days!</span></p>



<h1>Ditch the deal mindset &amp; focus on Cash flow</h1>



<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-2380 size-full" src="http://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/cashflow.png" alt="" width="389" height="129" srcset="https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/cashflow.png 389w, https://thedashafrica.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/cashflow-300x99.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 389px) 100vw, 389px" /><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Like a bouncing castle, when things get to the low and rigid you will not jump once and get to the sky, there are many warm-up jumps till the mega jump and this calls for patience.  To be a buffalo hunter is to know that you will not shoot at first glance often, you must first study the surroundings and the prey’s defense system and all your walk out moves</span>.</p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Businesses face chunks of challenges and opportunities and these too demand different solutions.  Good cash flow control is important for any business that wants to generate profit. Many businesses before have been focusing on profit even when cash flow is negative, this is going to change, a negative cash flow business will likely not survive.  Your Inflow creditors are going to reduce on morale and payers are going to learn the tactic to delay payments to build their cash flow too. You can guess how tough it will be. </span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Making the best use of your finances should be a key driver. Every element of working capital should be carefully controlled to maximize your cash flow. Knowing how to extend or fasten payment of debts, taking loans and making payments will all be great game changers.</span></p>



<p>DON&#8217;T MISS OUT MORE of <strong><a href="http://www.nicholaskquest.com"> LIGHT-SPEED Insights!</a></strong> from my platform.  </p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/future-readiness-8-lessons-entrepreneurs-must-keep-at-heart/">Future-readiness – 8 Lessons Entrepreneurs must keep at Heart.</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2022/02/01/future-readiness-8-lessons-entrepreneurs-must-keep-at-heart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should traditional banks get worried as Digital Banks trend?</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/should-traditional-banks-get-worried-as-digital-banks-trend-10-biggest-digital-banks-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/should-traditional-banks-get-worried-as-digital-banks-trend-10-biggest-digital-banks-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 09:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TheDash1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa's banking trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Automation and innovation is by far taking over the globe and this is not leaving the banking sector as well. Traditional banks must be headed to the...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/should-traditional-banks-get-worried-as-digital-banks-trend-10-biggest-digital-banks-in-2021/">Should traditional banks get worried as Digital Banks trend?</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Automation and innovation is by far taking over the globe and this is not leaving the banking sector as well. Traditional banks must be headed to the ruins if they haven&#8217;t seen this wave.  With artificial intelligence (AI) at the core of these digital transformations, Increased consumer demand for digital banking services is now unrivaled. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><em>But what exactly is digital banking?  How did it evolve over time, and where is the future of digital banking headed?</em></strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><em>What is about digital banking &amp; digital banking services?</em></strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Simply put, digital banking is the digitization of every  bank level, from front- to back-end, of banking. This means that digital banks rely on artificial intelligence to automate back-end operations such as administrative tasks and data processing which in turn alleviates pressure put on employees to complete day-to-day tasks while also lessening on human errors, corruption, conflict of interest and other human behavioral related incidences. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Digital banking is likely to be the next big thing.  Not only do digital banks allow users to make account deposits and transfers remotely; but they also provide them with the provisions to easily apply for loans of every kind and access personalized money management services, the system also creates a sense of data privacy since most banks can assess a borrower&#8217;s potential and collateral by capturing data on collateral and borrowing capacity digitally like bank statements, asset details, etc. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Online banking subsequently inspired mobile banking &#8211; the two summarizes digital banking as of today.  From the convenience of one’s mobile device such as a tablet or smartphone banking is getting a huge disruption ever in history. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">While most legacy banks now offer online services, digital-only banks are developed entirely electronically. Digital-only banks don’t lean on the financial and customer support from an established physical location, instead they’re powered via digital platforms that appeal to the millennial and General populations while leveraging on AI and other block-chain related technologies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The digital banking space is rapidly moving forward and is constantly changing. You may want to take a look at some key</span><span style="font-size: 14pt;"> biggest digital banks from different continents founded in the last 10 years, some thing that shows all the trend is growing tremendously.  Let&#8217;s look at a few dominating digital banks; </span></p>
<h1><a href="https://kuda.com/"><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Kuda </span></a></h1>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Nigeria &#8211; Africa.  &#8211; </span></strong></p>
<h3 class="LC20lb MBeuO DKV0Md">Free Banking for Nigerians</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Having started out as an online-only savings and lending platform, Kuda Bank is offering effective solutions for the common people.  It is  the first digital-only bank with a standalone license in Nigeria. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Kuda has focused on customer service and introducing user-friendly money management services, allowing its approximately 300,000 customers to manage payments, use cards and make physical deposits..  </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The bank uses a machine learning algorithm to tailor its services to each customer, which forms an important element of its credit offering.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 24pt;"><strong><a href="https://nubank.com.br/en/">Nubank</a></strong></span></h1>
<ul>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Founded in 2013, </span><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Based in Sao Paulo, Brazil</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">35 million customers</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">NUBANK is revered to be the largest fintech in Latin America Brazil and was founded in 2013.  This neobank</span><span style="font-size: 14pt;"> rolled out its first credit card in 2014. It was the only financial product that they could launch at that time as they couldn’t acquire a banking license in Brazil because the law was barring foreign bank ownership.  Most digital banks have gone through the barriers of regulatory restrictions but have found their way out. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The lucrative Brazilian banking market welcome their idea and product as credit card.  It was easy for them to lure in new customers with invite-only applications and by offering a credit card without any fees that you could apply for online and get in only two days.  </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In 2016, Nubank already had 1 million credit card customers with hardly any money spent on marketing. May 2017, Nubank received its full Brazilian banking license by presidential decree.  </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">By 2021, Nubank had around 35 million customers and had raised a total of $1.5 billion in capital fund.</span></p>
<h1><a href="https://www.chime.com/"><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Chime</span></a></h1>
<ul>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Founded in 2013</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">San Francisco, USA</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">12 million customers</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Founded in 2013 and </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;"> launched publicly in 2014 by surprise on a media show with a Chime card.  </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">With more than 12 million customers and a 50% growth through the pandemic.  Their focus is on</span><span style="font-size: 14pt;"> Americans who earn between $30,000 and $75,000 a year that have recognized that they can save significant amounts of money with a digital bank that has no fees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The digital banks future looks very bright as it is venturing into a stock market flotation that could make their valuation blow up to up to $ 50 Billions.  Experts predict. </span></p>
<h1><a href="https://www.tinkoff.ru/">TINKOFF</a></h1>
<ul>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Founded in 2006</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Russia</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">13 million customers</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Tinkoff Bank was founded in 2006 as Tinkoff Credit Systems.  It rolled out its first credit cards in 2007 and attracted attention from big-shot investing firms.  </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">They are now the second-largest credit card issuer holding 14% of Russia’s credit card market.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In 2011, they launched a mobile banking platform and after raising $90 million in 2012, they were ready for IPO on the London Stock Exchange that brought in a further $1.1 billion.  </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In 2015, the company finally rebranded to Tinkoff Bank.   Now a fully fledged digital bank in Russia. </span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 24pt;"><a href="https://monzo.com/">Monzo</a></span></h1>
<ul>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Founded in 2015</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">London, England</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">5 million customers</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Monzo was founded in 2015 and was One of the earliest digital banks in the UK. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The digital banking app  raised £1 million and in 2018, Monzo had reached one million customers with the total number of customers now reaching over 5 million.</span></p>
<h1><a href="https://www.judo.bank/"><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Judo Bank</span></a></h1>
<ul>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Founded in 2018</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"> Australia</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">10k customers</span></p></blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Based in Australia, Judo Bank, was founded in 2016 and got its banking license in 2019 and started out by focusing on Australia’s SMEs but is now also offering term deposits to regular Australians. </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Judo has the least amount of customers of around 10,000 estimate because they aren’t focusing on the retail segment for now. </span></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/should-traditional-banks-get-worried-as-digital-banks-trend-10-biggest-digital-banks-in-2021/">Should traditional banks get worried as Digital Banks trend?</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/should-traditional-banks-get-worried-as-digital-banks-trend-10-biggest-digital-banks-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five uncommon ways to make massive sales with ease!</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/four-uncommon-ways-to-make-massive-sales/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/four-uncommon-ways-to-make-massive-sales/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 08:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TheDash1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Every business person will tell you about sales in the first 10 minutes you may talk to them about their business. It is a very broad and...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/four-uncommon-ways-to-make-massive-sales/">Five uncommon ways to make massive sales with ease!</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Every business person will tell you about sales in the first 10 minutes you may talk to them about their business. It is a very broad and essential part of any business.  According to <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/sale.asp">Investopedia,</a>  A sale is a transaction between two or more parties in which the buyer receives tangible or intangible goods, services, or assets in exchange for money. Regardless how you define it, sales is the backbone of every business.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Sales has a hard mastery and that is why people go about it all wrong.  Good sales is rare. It is awesome.  So how do we go around sales?  This is my random thinking as I learn from many mentors making it in the business space. I have practiced most of the things and I can guarantee that its a big move. Just a look into the simple process of making massive sales, this is a foundation not an overall sale technique. </span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 24pt;">1. Sit in the customers&#8217; view</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Getting into a customers shoes and see what they see, feel what they feel, understand what they consciously need  is very game changing.  Put much focus  on them, their story and their business , their needs, their worries and they desired solutions in mind. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Sit back and dress in their shoes.  Take notes. Research. Observe. </span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">After all that flex their focus back to their current situation by asking, &#8220;How&#8217;s this and that&#8230;…  Your life, business, economy, situations, etc?&#8221;   This simple question gets them to think about where they are now: the good and the bad. They&#8217;ll likely share some good news with you, but also focus on what they&#8217;re unhappy with.  As they unveil, now you shall be ready to position well your solution and proposal and I am sure this will hit the right spot always.  This shall </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">allow them to consciously reveal most things about them without you over pushing or over guessing while hitting bad spots.  Take notes, translate and position better. </span></p>
<h1><strong><span style="font-size: 24pt;">2. Take the vision with them</span></strong></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In number 1 above, we had understood who they are, what they need and what they desire to have and what could be their major challenges.  Now be part of their solution visualization.   Tactically learn </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">their plans for the future, learn about their goals, their values, etc.  That way, you will master how to position the more and lessen chances of their rejection. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Knowing currents of a customer is not effective. You also need their movement surge so you can position well. You need to know to where the wind and waves are blowing to so that you don&#8217;t get left out sooner as the future folds. To work better and make massive easy sales, you must learn and help this  potential customers&#8217; trends in front of them, and realize what&#8217;s holding them back and then guide them to get there &#8211; eventually making a sale. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>SUMMARY OF THE ABOVE</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Client ABC is struggling with slow production and thus making little sales of  units in a year something crippling his business  (the current situation and problem to solve)</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="font-size: 14pt;">He wants an automated high production machine that can make 1000 units per week so he can increase his market demand and coverage and make more sales in the future while dominating the industry (the vision and desire, the goal and aspiration)</span></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong> </strong></span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 24pt;">3. Highlight the gap</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Now that we have known the problem by sitting in their view and also known their visions, desire and aspirations, it&#8217;s time to highlight the possible linkages to take them from between where they are and where they want to be.  If they are engaging, </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;"> allow them to describe this gap first, don’t do it for them at first hand. Remember you are less of a sales person but much of a consultant in the field. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">After getting their side of the gap, now in detail explain as an expert, in detail what needs to happen to change the narrative.   Highlight what support they may need the most.  And the scope or duration and resources to make that happen with ease. Advice and suggest. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"> Teach and engage them more if they feel still stuck. Don&#8217;t just explain. engage until the conversation gets into solidarity mode. Let them agree with you and get convinced that this is the best they can do,.  show them possibility of this happening. Show them better ways and alternatives. Do this with ease and don&#8217;t be pushy. Listen to their opinions and other worries or suggestions. Answer their questions and validate every inquiry they make. </span></p>
<h1>4. Now you can make the proposal</h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Until now, you have been dabbling and trying to create rapport and understanding. You have got all. Now, stand and put your kneel down and make that proposal. You must make it engaging too. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Offer them your solution. And get me well,  this isn&#8217;t about how you can help them, but rather helping them see that this is the help they need.  Once you describe the solution, ask them, if this would be valuable to them. Wait, not just valuable to them but if it is valuable towards overcoming their current situation and making their life or business better and making their vision come true. Explain and confirm they get how the solutions makes that happen. </span></p>
<h1>5. Let them Commit</h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">If they are clicking and getting things right then you are closer to making a sales. What next, make them commit. You are now specific on your offer and they have appreciated it. Now ask them to commit. Let them say yes to the proposal ring.  As you can see, there is no manipulation or scarcity tactics that make clients hate sales people. It looks so romantic that even the sales person likes the process. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">By using this process, even  if the proposal doesn&#8217;t get clicked,  the client will still always remember and happy that they had known about you, Guess what? Another relationship may be developed or future sale initiated. Most important this process will also make you feel happy because you helped someone recognize their problem and the way to overcome it, you will also learn from them many things that may better your craft in the next prospect and work life. You may also learn about what services or product or gain you can get from them. It is always two way. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">If you want to know more about many hacks for business acceleration, at our consultancy firm, <a href="https://nbkpremier.com/"><strong>NBK-PREMIER SOLUTIONS LTD</strong></a>  we offer state of the art guidance on how to make massive growth with ease. <a href="https://nbkpremier.com/">Contact us.</a>  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I wish you joy and breakthrough. I hope this article gives you insight to make more leads. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Until next time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Call me, Quest</span></p>
<p>Learn more about me <a href="http://www.nicholaskquest.com"><strong>HERE</strong></a></p>


<p></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/four-uncommon-ways-to-make-massive-sales/">Five uncommon ways to make massive sales with ease!</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/four-uncommon-ways-to-make-massive-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Profession based Entrepreneurs Go Broke (It&#8217;s shocking)</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/11-reasons-why-profession-based-entrepreneurs-go-broke-some-are-shocking/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/11-reasons-why-profession-based-entrepreneurs-go-broke-some-are-shocking/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 07:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TheDash1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Training and Coaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t know about you, but to my case I have always felt like I was born an entrepreneur. This means even the professions I have, I...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/11-reasons-why-profession-based-entrepreneurs-go-broke-some-are-shocking/">Why Profession based Entrepreneurs Go Broke (It’s shocking)</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I don&#8217;t know about you, but to my case I have always felt like I was born an entrepreneur. This means even the professions I have, I practice them as entrepreneurship. So, I have the audacity and all rights shade some light on this topic. To get to the topic faster, most professional based entrepreneurs struggle to make a financial breakthrough with their business, some stop on earning enough to pay the bills and the story ends.  Having been a victim of the same at some moment, I found it important to shade some light on the topic. Let&#8217;s move faster! </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Poor business model &#8211; if at all they do have. </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">If you are not an entrepreneur, I know we shall argue about this, but the reality is that the foundation of every great business is a great business model.  To make things practical let&#8217;s learn what a business model is.  Common definition via Wikipedia explains that a business model describes how an &#8220;organization&#8221; creates, delivers, and captures value, in economic, social, cultural or other contexts. If you keenly read, I quoted organization, this means business models are well implemented in a structural setting of a team.  Most profession based entrepreneurs like coaches, consultants, accountants, bloggers, lawyers, etc. don’t have any experience running a real business, they have knowledge but not experience. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">They are a one man show and one face hustle.  It’s not their fault, it’s not like this is taught at university where they graduated and they likely either worked for someone else in a corporate environment where everything that wasn’t their responsibility got taken care of, or they might have mastered one aspect of a business like PR and marketing but once they become the entrepreneurs they realize too late that they need to master much more than that one thing.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Most don&#8217;t have a business model that can leverage or build continuous momentum to get out of the dreaded inconsistent business of professions.  They just land on gigs and then get stuck and eventually either go broke or quit to try to get a real job again.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I have built countless business models and I have consulted for  countless coaches and consultants, and  I can tell you the impact of a business model.  8/10 professional based entrepreneurs don&#8217;t even know what a model is. They just drift. Don&#8217;t be like them! </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 24pt;">The Qualification syndrome</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Name them all, from all sections, coaches, trainers, accountants, etc. fall into the trap of feeling like they need to take their qualifications as a big deal, they spend too much time proving to be the guru, and feel everything needs to stem from their qualifications entitlement rather than knowledge delivered. The truth is, nobody cares how many degrees you have, how big your brand is, or whether you have all the accreditations and academic qualifications unless all that delivers a solution to them. Get me well, Qualifications matter  but when the work gets rolling, what customers care about is if you can solve their problems, period. And to do that you just need to throw the hat of qualifications and noble motivations and  just have to be committed to solving people’s problems. Fold the sleeve and focus on what matters &#8211; addressing customer needs.  That&#8217;s how referrals are built. Customers shall only refer a person who solved their problems with ease, no one will refer you just because you have a Ph.D. or what accreditation unless all that is attached to a huge skill popular for easy and great service delivery. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Drifting instead of mastery</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">&#8220;Jerk of all trades, master of none&#8221;. &#8211; I guess you ever heard of the saying.  You don’t have to be an implementor or expert at everything, don&#8217;t practice the superman syndrome; Marketing, sales, team building, leadership, systems thinking, to name a few all require you to master not all of them but how they work, simply put; management of those who run them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You need to master what you can master and outsource what you can afford at the time.   Don&#8217;t drift at many things and end up mustering none. You can be good at branding but suck at mobilization, don&#8217;t make your energy drain while drifting. Master a thing do it, influence other master do what you struggle with too, that way the hustle shall be productive beyond measure. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Insufficient &amp; ineffective focus on business Development</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You all know this.  It&#8217;s a huge blow and hard reality to get to terms with.  Any profession based service is a business regardless of its nature.  Even a freelancer have got their operational expenses.  We all know a business can’t exist very long unless it makes enough money to cover its expenses and turn a profit. And in order to do that, you have to be able to market and sell your products or services more efficiently than the vast majority of others out there in the competitive marketplace. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You will believe me that most profession based entrepreneurs are still trapped in the myth of ego and they market small, or sometimes if they do, they do in a sucking way. The trends have changed. Marketing in this noisy world must be taken on deliberately, else the aggressive street chaps will take over.  No wonder you see unqualified men and women running errands that used to be for high end law firms. Because &#8216;most&#8217; lawyers, minus the regulations of their industry, they still don&#8217;t know how to place themselves up for business. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The world is noisy more than ever, and you can&#8217;t just make it by keeping the siren mute. You need to fill that gap, regardless of the niche you occupy. You need to be <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GET-SHAP-REIMAGINED-THOUGHTS-BUSINESS/dp/B08HTM7VKY">SEEN, HEARD &amp; Eventually paid</a>.  there are a whole lot of things to do to get there and i share some in my book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GET-SHAP-REIMAGINED-THOUGHTS-BUSINESS/dp/B08HTM7VKY"><span style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #0000ff;"><strong>GET SHAP (Get Seen Heard  and Paid)</strong></span></a> Get the Book <a href="_wp_link_placeholder" data-wplink-edit="true"><strong>HERE</strong></a> Now.  </span></p>
<p><iframe title="GET SHAP: REIMAGINED THOUGHTS TO LEVEL UP YOUR BUSINESS AND CAREER" type="text/html" width="640" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?preview=inline&#038;linkCode=kpd&#038;ref_=k4w_oembed_ym4RzQZ1r1krCo&#038;asin=B08HTM7VKY&#038;tag=kpembed-20"></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">As a professional based entrepreneur, you need to get over any fears, misconceptions or false beliefs about marketing and sales, you need to break the myths.  Positioning, branding and marketing are the skills that any entrepreneur MUST master in order to find any level of financial and business success in the professional world. You are not a professional to just make money for bills, but you also need to buy that uptown building block, build a home and have a wealth of your own.  So,  G<strong>et SHAP!  </strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It’s a simple creative thinking approach.  Don’t be a dud.  Invest in learning what it takes to turn a stranger into a happy, paying client with ease like the BIG Boys do. . It’s not that hard, but there is a right and wrong way to do it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">With my experience, I know for certain that marketing and sales makes all the difference between success and failure. Money can solve most business problems, and a lack of it causes most businesses problems. Simple enough.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Not having systems &amp; Standards</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Again, we must agree that any business requires systems and standards Lack of systems an standards can cause business fractures and bruises. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">From documentation, quality control,  records, customer interactions, transactions, regulatory requirements and so on, business regardless of their size require certain standards and systems fully functional to beat competition and have smooth productive operations. Systems and standards are an essential part of the business.   Systems and standards are used by both small and big businesses to demonstrate their ability to consistently provide products and services that meet customer and regulatory requirements under acceptable disciplines. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Fueling the rate race!</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Hard to understand but if you talked to any professional based entrepreneur you will know what i am talking about. Some tactically spend time hustling to get clients, then get full and then get busy executing the obligations, and guess what? in that period they put the foot off the marketing pedal and all of a sudden as they finish the tasks they are back to zero again. Then takes more time without leads hunting for more.  Get, cover previous idle time expenses, get busy serving them and rinse. Back to square one.  You get it? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Instead of creating a continuous systematic marketing processes they keep in an unending rat race, starting over from square one each month and having many idle days. Just to remind you;  every bill you pay is due every month regardless of whether you had work or not.  Meaning any idle period you get with no leads,  your future income suffers a deficit. Unsubscribing off the rat race is key to make the business work at times. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 24pt;">Unnecessary Skyrocketing </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It&#8217;s like bringing a boiling electric kettle coil to warm or boil the ocean.  Simply put most of these people have Huge and too broad offers. You must find a niche figured out to filter what leads to target other than burning resources and dropping here and there proposals that wont be received with recognitions.   You don&#8217;t need to shoot the skies who birds are not impactful. Focus on your target areas with masterly as you build new ones.  Don&#8217;t just dabble around. </span></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/11-reasons-why-profession-based-entrepreneurs-go-broke-some-are-shocking/">Why Profession based Entrepreneurs Go Broke (It’s shocking)</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/27/11-reasons-why-profession-based-entrepreneurs-go-broke-some-are-shocking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Behind TotalEnergies&#8217; change of name &#038; new vision</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/behind-total-energies-change-of-name-new-vision/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/behind-total-energies-change-of-name-new-vision/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 13:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TheDash1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a bid to reinvent the energy sector, giant energy firm, TOTAL ENERGIES reimagined its strategy that led to change of its name previously.  Talk of Energy...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/behind-total-energies-change-of-name-new-vision/">Behind TotalEnergies’ change of name & new vision</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>In a bid to reinvent the energy sector, giant energy firm, TOTAL ENERGIES reimagined its strategy that led to change of its name previously. </strong></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Talk of Energy companies dominating across the globe, and I am sure you won&#8217;t miss the French giant, Total SE.  A few months back <strong>TOTAL SE,</strong> announced a change of its name to <strong><a href="https://totalenergies.com/">TotalEnergies</a></strong> as the company moves to the lead of world’s top five in renewables by 2030. In tandem with this name change,  Mr Patrick Pouyanné, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of TotalEnergies said TotalEnergies was adopting a new visual identity. An extract of his speech below clearly gives what the secret behind TOTALENERGIES was about; </span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">‘’<em>I would like to thank our Shareholders for their almost unanimous support on our new name, TotalEnergies, that anchors our strategy in our identity, as well as for their support by a very large majority, more than 90%, on the resolution on the Company’s ambition with respect to sustainable development and energy transition towards carbon neutrality and its related targets by 2030.</em></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>The shareholders voted by a very large majority in favour of this resolution because they perceive the real transformation process in which the company is engaged and have made this vote support of a bold and demanding strategy.</em></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>This very strong support also means a great demand and a huge commitment for us, the women and men of TotalEnergies. This transformation into a broad energy company that places sustainable development at the heart of its strategy, its projects and its operations is a transformation that will mobilize the entire company. The reality is that TotalEnergies is becoming one of the most active players in the energy transition.”  </em>He said,</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In a statement issued by the company and posted on its website on May 28,  2021,  after the resolution of the Board of Directors at the Ordinary and Extraordinary Shareholders’ meeting, held on Friday, May 28, 2021, by the oil and gas firm in Paris, France, said the shareholders approved, almost unanimously, the resolution to change the company’s name from Total to TotalEnergies, thereby anchoring its strategic transformation into a broad energy company in its identity.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>TOTAL is a broad energy company that produces and markets energies on a global scale: oil and biofuels, natural gas and green gases, renewables and electricity.</strong></span></p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>TOTAL is also active in more than 130 countries, TotalEnergies puts sustainable development in all its dimensions at the heart of its projects and operations to contribute to the social welfare, economic development and environmental protection.</strong></span></p></blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><span style="color: #333399;">“Energy is reinventing itself, and this energy journey is ours. Our ambition is to be a world-class player in the energy transition. That is why Total is transforming and becoming TotalEnergies.”</span></strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>&#8211; Pouyanne, te CEO,</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">TOTAL SE has recently emerged as one of the front runners among oil and gas firms in terms of embracing renewable energy, with a 100 gigawatts gross target for 2030 that is among the largest of any player globally.  In a further release, the company communicated that it will allocate 20% of net investments to renewables and “low carbon power” for the years ahead.  That should equate to over $2.4 billion, up from $2 billion in 2020.  That has already seen it take big positions in solar in the US, Spain and India, and in offshore wind in the UK and most recently Taiwan and many other countries in Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">“This new name and new visual identity embody the course TotalEnergies has resolutely charted for itself; that of a broad energy company committed to producing and providing energies that are ever more affordable, reliable, and clean,”   &#8211;  A statement posted on its website further said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>&#8220;Energy is life. We all need it and it’s a source of progress. So today, to contribute to the sustainable development of the planet facing the climate challenge, we are moving forward, together, towards new energies. Energy is reinventing itself, and this energy journey is ours. Our ambition is to be a world-class player in the energy transition. That is why Total is transforming and becoming TotalEnergies. Discover the elements of our transformation on: totalenergies.com/energy-is-reinventing-itself&#8221;  </em>  An awareness notice video further states from their website.</span></p>
<p>https://youtu.be/XrVU-4q3snw</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Energy experts say oil companies are rebranding fast to send a message to the public and investors about their commitment to change business models to prepare for a low-carbon future.  Energy is what the world is made of and in my opinion, this reinvent of its future is a great move as spear headed by TOTAL SE &#8211; now TotalEnergies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In September 2021, via the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/totalenergies-outlook-idAFP6N2OI02P">Reuters,</a></span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">  in Paris, TotalEnergies officials said that the company expected a big rise in renewable-based electricity, solar and wind forms of energy, partly due to a general increase in electrification in the industrial and business world. They added that they </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">expected that oil in general would plateau before 2030, while natural gas would continue to play a role as a transition fuel.</span></p>
<p class="Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x"><span style="font-size: 18.6667px;">This possibly gives an awakening insight behind the self-reinvention of the company &#8211; Predicting and positioning for the lucrative renewable energy future.   </span></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/behind-total-energies-change-of-name-new-vision/">Behind TotalEnergies’ change of name & new vision</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/behind-total-energies-change-of-name-new-vision/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are you an Entrepreneur?  Her Story will shock you!</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/is-everyone-meant-to-be-a-s-h-a-p-entrepreneur/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/is-everyone-meant-to-be-a-s-h-a-p-entrepreneur/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 08:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entreprneur advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small business success tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedashafrica.com/?p=2200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“Bandwagons roll through our lives. It’s up to you whether you jump on them unquestioningly or jump on them to overturn them and subvert them”. &#8211;  Riz...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/is-everyone-meant-to-be-a-s-h-a-p-entrepreneur/">Are you an Entrepreneur?  Her Story will shock you!</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><em>“Bandwagons roll through our lives. It’s up to you whether you jump on them unquestioningly or jump on them to overturn them and subvert them”.</em></strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>&#8211;  Riz Ahmed</strong></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Beyond a shadow of doubt, deciding to stick to my entrepreneurship course every other new day is the drive that makes me carry on. For me, being an entrepreneur is the conduit through which I feel empowered to cause impact and achieve my highest potential. Whereas it may look beautiful on the outside, there are many stories that may frighten you too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In my field as a serial entrepreneur and consultant, I have had horrifying experiences that have left me on the edge of collapse alongside the unrivalled bliss. When the stressful experiences show up, it is often easier to consider giving up as the first alternative. However, keeping on and holding on to the rope has helped me to re-spark off again. Whereas I calculate my moves and work on my messes quick and strike back like any other SHAP entrepreneur, there are stories of other people I meet that surpass my understanding. The stories of businesses, ideas, resources and dreams that got sharked never to be seen again.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Just because people are making it huge in a given business does not mean if you start the same you will make it too. The truth is, if you follow the bandwagon effect to start a business, you are likely going to run at a loss and the business may fold.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">When the business closes, usually your life too is affected. You need to do your homework before launching a business and this homework starts with you. Very many people don’t do a self-consciousness analysis to know who they are in relation to the business they want while others just fall for the bandwagon effect.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Some time back, I spoke at a conference in Entebbe alongside other prominent industry thought leaders including Mr. Chapman, one of my greatest business heroes. It was a humbling moment where everyone was excited to learn and network from one another. As a guest speaker, I shared tens of mistakes I have made as a young serial entrepreneur and how I bounced back from the effects. As a consultant, I highlighted some non-conventional hacks to a successful business. And as realist, I shared breath taking stories of my whole journey; people, failures and lost opportunities along my journey.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">To the conclusion of my talk, a young lady burst into tears and a wail that shook the audience.  The wail got her off her seat to the podium and straight into my arms resulting into a tight gripping hug with her tears flowing over on my shoulders. Everyone wondered what had happened. For a moment I was stuck in awe. <em>Had I hurt her?</em> I somehow wondered. Well, you are guessing it wrong, she was not hurt; they were tears of relief after a long time of holding on to a loss she had made<em>.   &#8220;I wish I had known about this before I made that decision, Nicholas.&#8221;</em> She tearfully repeated the words.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 18pt;">Her Story</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">She had a dream like any other person while she was working with an international NGO. She saved and invested her earnings in treasury bills for a number of years.  She dreamed of starting up her own business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">She had saved and accumulated more than 100,000 USD (<em>more than UGX 380,000,000</em>). Yes, over Uganda shillings 380  million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">She had never considered seeking professional help on business and money matters as she thought she would handle it all. She wanted to play her game like a catholic prayer (<em>in isolation, humbleness and silence</em>). So she took un-informed approaches and started a business backed by hope and a conventional wish of prayer. She had learnt of a growing need for organic cosmetics, shampoos and perfumes (which was true – there was a great gap at the time).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">She believed that before making thorough technical research and consultancy on how to structure the business, the distribution channels, sales and all that involves breaking through. She assumed people would buy once stock arrived given the demand without really knowing the dynamics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Long story short, she shipped cosmetics from Dubai only to be blown away by the high taxes and the never ending clearing processes she never knew about. To recover from the deep investment with a profit, she needed to have a better recovery plan. Unfortunately, she did not have a well-organized team that would be in position to effect a timely sale &amp; distribution at a profit.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Many items were still in store by the third month. On purchasing, she had not factored in the element of sales time against the longevity of the products. By the fifth month, some of the products had started expiring and yet not even half of the stock was sold. She tried some kind of <strong><em>&#8220;all must Go”</em></strong> discount sale with big wholesalers but there was also another flood of other cosmetics from senior distributors, so no one bought in bulk.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">By the 7<sup>th</sup> month, she found herself stuck with some expired products that were not needed anywhere on the market. The authorities came in and the products had to be laid to pit and burnt.  She lost her long-term savings due to making uninformed decisions. The experience left her drowned in an ocean of stress that she could not pay attention to her husband and son and her life as well. She was in a big slump.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">There are hundreds of similar stories around us every day. Sole, egoistic, emotional decision making is one of the biggest risk factors bringing such stories of deep rooted pain in the business world. Without a self-consciousness test, research, consultancy, market study and testing, we end up hurting ourselves. It takes good time, consultations, and meetings to launch a great business that makes you seen, heard and paid. This is not to say that doing all this guarantees success but then you need a road map for the foreseeable future.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The biggest challenge I find is that aspiring and existing business owners opine that investing in analysis personal growth, research and consultancy is a waste of resources and time only for them to make irreversible and expensive mistakes at the end. This is not to say that you have to know everything but the basics should be at hand if your objective is to be<strong> seen, heard and paid</strong>.  If you are thinking of doing business, make sure you have an informed roadmap that can help you make informed decisions. Always take the necessary steps, know yourself and what position you hold in relation to your big dream. Sometimes, a third perspective can make a difference.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Few days later after the seminar, I sat with her to establish a new footing. We spent 26 days working together every day in my businesses and our clients’ businesses allowing her to run work in different positions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I un-coached and coached her of many soft and hard skills sharing with her what we did wrong and what we did right. I also shared with her what our weaknesses are and I took her on a personal journey of healing, I cautioned her to take every small word, act or process seriously, analyze it and pick lessons.  She then embarked on a new journey to re-start her business and luckily, her husband agreed to lend her $1500 &amp; $1000 more from her friends. This time round, she went in for a vegetable and fruit packaging supply business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The first emphasis was on growth and systems. We designed and documented safety plans, packaging and storage systems, delivery processes, payment policies, etc. We ensured she got the standard certifications gradually as she got more money.  She was skeptical why we had to over document and systemize things, she got nervous at the start but we kept holding and stretching her beyond mind limits, each three days I had to report to her work place so that we can analyze what she was doing and strategize what next for her to land her first client.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Three months after the start, she recorded her first supply client; an uptown restaurant that would consume quite a variety of fruits and vegetables.  We had documented all her processes and safety policies and she had secured standard packaging materials.  She got her first supply from her farmer and market partners and we ensured she delivered successfully.  She was surprised at how designing processes and systems could make high end clients trust with ease.  She did that well and by the fifth month she had three more high-end clients and recorded her first net profit. Little ‘net profit’ of UGX 276,550 (around $70) and this was a very exciting moment for her however small. It was a signal of a health business as she had kept cash flow positive all the months.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">She mastered the discipline and with time her business picked course. Today, three years later, she runs an eight figure (UGX) net profit business supplying over a dozen restaurants and hotels on a daily and supporting tens of farmers. Her life has changed and is no longer the woman that broke into a wail of tears at a seminar. She now employs 5 drivers and 9 other support workers and other dozens of people part-timely. She has established a packaging and storage facility too and  she is on a better footing and recently got a high end supply contract with some IOC <em>(International Oil Company)</em>. This all happened when she decided to be deliberate about her business journey.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Taking the hard way has seen her climb to the highest peaks of business.  <em>“I was so foolish, Nicholas, I would not have lost that 100k in cosmetics,”</em> She often tells as she reminisces on the past.  As I quoted <strong>Riz Ahmed</strong> at the beginning of this chapter;<em> “Bandwagons roll through our lives. It’s up to us whether to jump on them unquestioningly or jump on them to overturn them and subvert them.”..</em></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This is an extract from my book dubbed:  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GET-SHAP-REIMAGINED-THOUGHTS-BUSINESS/dp/B08HTM7VKY/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr="><strong><span id="productTitle" class="a-size-extra-large">GET SHAP: The Modus Operandi for Radical Entrepreneurs!  </span></strong></a></span></p>
<p><iframe title="GET SHAP: REIMAGINED THOUGHTS TO LEVEL UP YOUR BUSINESS AND CAREER" type="text/html" width="640" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?preview=inline&#038;linkCode=kpd&#038;ref_=k4w_oembed_ZoP1eB18ZHi7Uv&#038;asin=B08HTM7VKY&#038;tag=kpembed-20"></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You an as well make local print orders in EAST AFRICA via +256704597816</span></p>
<p>What&#8217;s your story?  Write to us:  legacyafrica.uganda@gmail.com</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Learn more about my work at <a href="http://www.nicholaskquest.com">www.nicholaskquest.com </a></span></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/is-everyone-meant-to-be-a-s-h-a-p-entrepreneur/">Are you an Entrepreneur?  Her Story will shock you!</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2021/11/26/is-everyone-meant-to-be-a-s-h-a-p-entrepreneur/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Customer Alignment &#038; Flow</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/tough-competitors-in-the-finals/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/tough-competitors-in-the-finals/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 12:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TheDash1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attracting customers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flow. nicholaskquest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to get customers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/mysterythemes/matina-news/?p=80</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“People don’t like to be sold to, but they love to buy” &#8211; Jeffrey Gitomer “Stay out of here; it’s a ‘No snack’ week”. So my heart...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/tough-competitors-in-the-finals/">Customer Alignment & Flow</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong><em>“People don’t like to be sold to, but they love to buy”</em></strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">&#8211; Jeffrey Gitomer</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>“Stay out of here; it’s a ‘No snack’ week”. </em>So my heart tells me parked outside of <a href="https://cafejavas.co.ug/"><strong>Cafe Javas</strong></a>, a fast foods restaurant in Kampala Uptown, debating whether to go inside or not. I stare at their vibrant interior, then start battling my appetite as I weigh the pros and cons. <em>“Do I really want the snack?  Is my craving stronger than my desire to stick with my “No snack week”?” </em> As I contemplate, for just a little longer it looks weird, I force a decision – Not to enter, and off I go. That was some day and I hope you can relate. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">On most days, I still have same contemplations on many things – whether to spend the 50k on eating out at the café or buy groceries and head home. Sometimes I go eat, and others I walk away.  </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">And whatever choice I make, I claim to be fulfilled with some stupid defense in mind, I say stupid because it is always a fact of consolation at times. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In business, this is in relation to the struggle that all prospective and current customers experience in the face of a purchase, and the challenges all businesses must overcome in order to grow and thrive. In this case, Café Javas is a business, I am a client. They must be doing something so that my showing up comes without a struggle.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It wasn’t always so hard when I was in my 20s, I never contemplated that much then. I would enter the café without pondering why. I had fewer options.  Today, my preferences have changed. These days when I am not out with my daughters, <em>bae </em>or friends, I prefer buying home groceries than spend at a café. I am strict with my choices now unlike then. I am not sure if the café owner knows that changing fact in me (imagining we are 100 clients with that behavior now).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">On a day that I decide to walk into a café, I order my favorite chicken samosa, when I do, the thing I don’t want to hear is someone give me options. <em>“We don’t have Chicken samosas but we have beef samosas, they are good too… blah blah”.</em>  And if it happens two or three times I always stop asking for the samosa all together. If it is not a darling place, I stop going back.  I have done this to many places.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">That’s the difference between buying and being sold to. Buying is when you want something and getting it. Being sold to is what happens when they say <em>“no, we can’t do/ have that, but..”</em>  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This is very common.  Buying has that magical payoff of wanting something and feeling like the king of the world because you’ve turned your own wish into reality.  Being sold to comes with coercion; someone trying to convince you with a substitute or what they consider a better alternative.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Don’t get me wrong. Sometimes there are very good reasons why the customer can’t have things exactly the way they want them. Those expectations may be poorly informed, or completely unreasonable but sometimes the customer even knows it but can play ignorant. Creating alignment isn’t easy; and yet that’s the name of the winning game. That’s what drives business; building a business that seems to align effortlessly.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #ff6600;">INTENDED BREAK</span></strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #ff6600;">NOTE: This article is an extract from the book <a style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #ff6600;" href="https://www.amazon.com/GET-SHAP-REIMAGINED-THOUGHTS-BUSINESS/dp/B08HTM7VKY/">GET SHAP &#8211; Reimagined thoughts to level up your business and career. </a></span></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="GET SHAP: REIMAGINED THOUGHTS TO LEVEL UP YOUR BUSINESS AND CAREER" type="text/html" width="640" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?preview=inline&#038;linkCode=kpd&#038;ref_=k4w_oembed_2aOkfwzB2Qeimw&#038;asin=B08HTM7VKY&#038;tag=kpembed-20"></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">There are three dimensions to alignment. The first of those dimensions is the <strong>Offer.</strong> Here you avail what the market wants. You position yourself as the best candidate to sell. The stronger that alignment, the more effortless growth seems to occur. Most business people at many times rush to increase advertising efforts and budget to transform business yet all they should be doing is align themselves. Consider two examples: <em>Jumia</em> and <em>Safe Boda</em>.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">On <a href="https://www.jumia.ug/"><em>Jumia</em>,</a> you search for mostly daily use items you could need, and choose from any number of interesting payment options. When you find the item you want, you click just one button, and you’re done and go back to your comfort and wait for delivery at your door/gate.     </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">With <a href="https://www.safeboda.com/"><em>Safe Boda</em></a> as a customer they make your wish come true by ordering your ride from your comfort by just a click. Just like magic, <em>Jumia</em> and <em>Safe Boda</em> and their ilk continue growing because they have found their flow with technology. That way, through technology, they have aligned themselves to their clients. They have built a great offer delivered by a <strong>resonant identity</strong>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Of course many competitors have come up but none has defeated them because of their customer flow and alignment.   </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Don’t get confused, we can’t do all the things customers want. There will be unmet expectations because those wants and expectations are unreasonable, or impractical. Or at times, we know that they won’t actually deliver the results that the customer ultimately wants.  E.g. I’d love it if I ordered a Safe Boda rider to pick me and be very neat in suits. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">That way, I would feel so high sitting behind this rider. But wait, this is impossible and unreasonable, riders are middle life people, and they don’t go into all that luxurious living. The safety code too doesn’t allow that smart dressing with no warm jackets and all. Customer alignment calls for understanding and filtering of such crucial matters and craft a perfect model.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Each and every <em>“no, we can’t do that, but&#8230;”</em> must be followed by a compelling explanation, else it becomes an opportunity for your prospective customer to consider walking away. That’s why, as entrepreneurs seeking to build flow in our businesses, we must think long and hard about all the different things our audience wants or expects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I have had many dates in my life. I am glad I have had, they have taught me too much.  I surely prefer second dates to first ones. First dates can feel a bit exciting but are expensive and require a lot of hard work. They can be tricky and funny. Most times they are sugar coated, the personality you see is always ironed to fit in the date and impress.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">When you pass first date’s trickiness, that’s when you get to have a second date. Second dates are easier.  You are now in the equation. It is the beginning of reality and shading off of the masks.  I’m not talking about romantic dates by the way (wink). This is about business, sales, and marketing.  My point is that second dates are times for you to build a real and resonant identity.  This leads me to the third piece of the puzzle; <strong>the Intuitive Path</strong>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This is about aligning your business with your prospective customer’s expectations and intuitions around what next step they should take at any given point. For example, you may want them to know:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The next thing they want to read or hear or see from you</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The next step you want them to take on a journey</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The next thing you want them to invest in (whether it’s their very first investment with you, or the next in a long series).</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The  more  the  next  step  you want  them to take aligns with what feels obvious and logical and right to them, the smoother that path will be. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This brings us back to planning a second date.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Good second dates combine two things:  First, they build on the relationship that has already been established. Secondly, they push things forward taking them to the next level.  These are both critical qualities; if things don’t move forward, then you find yourself in a string of dates that seem to go nowhere, and eventually you’re back to kissing frogs in search of a new prince or princess.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The two keys that you need to balance as you craft a path forward for your second date are: 1) Building on what’s already there. 2) Bringing things to the next level.  They both result into an intuitive path that your customers are eager and excited to follow.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">When the alignment is absent – that’s when you end up having to push hard on every sale like kicking a broken horse to move fast. When the alignment is just right, when you’re basically a darling product, then everything gets easier. The customers move forward and pay less attention to the shortcomings.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">They buy with blindness and support you.  They evangelize.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">There are interesting ways different cultures say hello. Back home, we say; <em>Agandi!, m</em>eaning <em>how is your life</em> (one beyond visibility, inner).  In some parts they just say;<em> Jambo, etc</em>. When I was living in the United Arab Emirates, I learnt that they say; <em>“Salam” </em>which means <em>“peace”.</em> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">And in India and some closer parts they say <em>Namaste,</em> which loosely translates as <em>“the light in me sees the light in you”.</em>  The latter greeting have always been the most interesting greeting that I use at the end of most blog articles &amp; speeches and I will use it to drive this point home.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It illustrates an important and powerful dimension on which we must all create alignment between our business and the people that it exists to serve. Of course, the first step towards making a sale is having something that people want but remember lots of other providers do the same as what you do or even better.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Choosing between multiple providers in today’s stiff competition will have a strong gut sense that one just <em>“feels right”</em> and then do the due diligence that allows their brain to sign off on the decision. That gut feeling comes from alignment <em>(offer, identity and intuitive path).</em> The light in them seeing the light in you, and recognizing it as the very same light. This draws us to the two main parts that form alignment; Relatability and Aspiration</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Relatability </strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Ever gone to a store or office and found everything not easy to relate with? When positioning you must keep in mind the element that when customers look at you, they see themselves. Because we implicitly trust and connect with people in whom we see ourselves. So they buy from relationship empathy on top of the need. Quality alone is not enough, there must also be some relatable attributes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This positioning comes in colors, message, overall brand image, structure, website, etc. It is not something tangible that you create but something psychological that you incorporate in your offerings and identity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>Aspiration</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You’ll find this balance in every leader and person or brand you’ve ever looked up to – and in every leader that you wish others would stop looking up to as well! That balance of <em>“You’re just like me, you represent my beliefs and feelings”</em> and <em>“I want to be like you when I grow up</em>” is exactly what is compelling to the audiences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">So that’s the key: find the ways in which you can portray that your offer, identity and intuitive path are in alignment with your market. The overall brand must speak to their emotions somehow. You have to empower the light in them to see the light in you. Alignment and its great hidden importance is a great deal to getting SHAP.  Make it a habit to see how it can be incorporated in your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">For more details, get the book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GET-SHAP-REIMAGINED-THOUGHTS-BUSINESS/dp/B08HTM7VKY/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr=">GET SHAP </a></span></p>
<p><iframe title="GET SHAP: REIMAGINED THOUGHTS TO LEVEL UP YOUR BUSINESS AND CAREER" type="text/html" width="640" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?preview=inline&#038;linkCode=kpd&#038;ref_=k4w_oembed_rO8U7MokjVeX4t&#038;asin=B08HTM7VKY&#038;tag=kpembed-20"></iframe></p>


<p>GET THE BOOK STORY HERE </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="GET SHAP - Nicholas K. Quest &amp; the story behind the book" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UiXhUPW9uEM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/tough-competitors-in-the-finals/">Customer Alignment & Flow</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/tough-competitors-in-the-finals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>If you are doing this, you are a Naked Emperor in business</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/impacts-of-remote-work/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/impacts-of-remote-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 12:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naked emperor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small business in uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/mysterythemes/matina-news/?p=76</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It is an old adage and  hope you heard of that tale; &#8220;The Emperor&#8217;s New Clothes&#8221;. It is a short tale written by Danish author Hans Christian...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/impacts-of-remote-work/">If you are doing this, you are a Naked Emperor in business</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It is an old adage and  hope you heard of that tale;<em> &#8220;The Emperor&#8217;s New Clothes&#8221;. </em>It is a short tale written by Danish author<em> Hans Christian Andersen</em>. It is about two weavers who promised an emperor a new suit that they said was invisible to those who are unfit for their positions, stupid, or incompetent – while in reality, they made no clothes at all, making everyone believe the clothes are invisible to them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">When the emperor paraded before his subjects in his new &#8220;clothes&#8221;, no one dared to say that they did not see any suit of clothes on him for fear that they would be seen as stupid.  Finally, a child cried out, &#8220;<em>But he isn&#8217;t wearing anything at all!&#8221; </em>and so others followed suit and cried too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Yikes! This is exactly the kind of thing you want to avoid in business. Do you want to be the naked emperor who thinks he’s wearing a magnificent suit and all the people around you keep quiet?  No. So don’t be the entrepreneur whose dumb ideas are applauded even when they are dumb to the dumbest of all. Be the entrepreneur whose employees and partners have the courage to say no and expose the nakedness of the emperor’s suit, your ideas can be crap and the weavers around you can be corny and tricky but the best employees and partners can say; <em>“Hey Emperor, you are naked”</em></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This applies to normal life as well. You don’t want to surround yourself with the weavers and fearful subjects. Such partners tell you your ideas are good but laugh behind your back. As <em>Simon Sinek</em> emphasizes; exponential organizations primarily focus on trust and honesty then secondary to performance, so with the novice entrepreneur. It’s total crap to have partners and employees who perform and execute your crappy ideas than having honest and trustworthy ones who will say <em>“Hey emperor, this idea makes us naked in long term”</em>.   In business, honesty to the emperor’s nakedness is better than empathy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You’re an entrepreneur and sometimes you fly by the seat of your pants and stray in thinking and behavior. Entrepreneurs need people who are positively skeptical and engaging.   So when you are hiring, you need to look past the yes-clan and find someone who will always refuse to kiss your dirty foot until they are cleaned.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The honest employee will challenge you, build on good ideas to make them better, and get you thinking about the flip side of things. Such people are not the wisest or most skilled and they don’t have all the answers, but by looking at things from a different light, with honest and skeptical eyes, they can point out things you might have missed, they are people worth keeping around.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Year 2012, there was no way I could have gotten to the heights I reached without my girlfriend then.  Not only were her ideas brilliant but also was she very honest with me and that included saying no to some of my ideas and plans. Even when I would defy, she had to be honest with me and believe me. This made me avoid many mistakes in life and work that would have consumed me.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Honesty (openness) is critical for any human relationship to succeed and it is so more critical in business too.  And when I say honesty, I don’t mean being faithful only but I also mean constructive realism and skepticism. You need people who are upfront with you. Not those who tell you one thing then go off and whisper something different in the corridor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">When you have employees agreeing with everything you say, your ego might start to get pretty big and fattened unknowingly and this is bad for business.   And you shouldn’t allow your ego to get in the way of business</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You need to opt for hiring people who keep you humble by pointing out the things you haven’t seen in a positive way and people you are able to freely associate with. They teach you new things and also remind you of the importance of staying grounded for the sake of building the business.  I watched one video online when <em>Jeff Bezos </em>the founder of Amazon was telling his employees that one day Amazon is liable to fall but their work was to delay its fall. That’s a great concept that can be understood by honest and open employees and partners who can look at you and say; <em>“Hey Emperor, you are naked”, </em>let’s dress up.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong>Caution of Importance </strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">All said and heard, as a caution of importance, you have to know that just because you hire people who are willing to give you other ideas doesn’t mean you always have to listen to them as well all the time. Sometimes, you need to listen to yourself. If you think you have a winning idea worth pursuing even after your employees give you blank stares and counter ideas, you don’t have to take their advice or all of it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">But also don’t make their effort feel less important, communicate to them and appreciate their efforts regardless of your decisions. You are the leader and sometimes non-conformist employees can choose to drive you nuts. So, stay grounded on the realities with respect always.  The goal is not whose idea wins but what idea builds the enterprise from ground up.</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 18pt;">Seek Integrity</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You may be thinking that you need to look for honesty in acts, truthfulness, trustworthiness, virtue, decency, etc. Not that much. In reality integrity is the state of being whole and undivided in whatever one is set to do let it be thoughts or actions. People with this kind of integrity have a sharp alignment of their thoughts and deeds. They are people who never have confusion of thoughts, they are true to the situations at present and themselves. These are the people you need because they will look at you and say; <em>“Hey Emperor, you are naked, please have this and dress up”</em></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong>What Mission?</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Are they people driven by a mission beyond their survival? Or, are they simply driven by short term ideas for short term gains?  Are they people who can sell tomorrow&#8217;s silver for today’s bread? We are here on this thing for long-term contribution, so that we gain by offering a service or product. People looking for a quick buck to survive on with no mission attached have always been disappointing to work with. It’s only when we have people looking beyond lunch that we can have exponential companies we can pride in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong>Fun &amp; Expression</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Scientists say that the average formal worker spends over 100,000 hours at work in a lifetime. This is the biggest part of every life. We must choose to work with people whose company we enjoy.   If you can&#8217;t have fun and free expression during work then that is absolutely a soul sacking partnership one must not be involved in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong>Brilliance and Dreams</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I love being around intelligent people with propelling dreams for bettering themselves and humanity. Everybody does, I guess.  You have to make it a point to know what your partners and employees are up to and how they can keep pressing for bigger things.  Such people make you push more when the terrains get steep.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This is an extract from a book dubbed <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GET-SHAP-REIMAGINED-THOUGHTS-BUSINESS/dp/B08HTM7VKY"><strong>GET SHAP</strong></a>.</span></p>
<p><iframe title="GET SHAP: REIMAGINED THOUGHTS TO LEVEL UP YOUR BUSINESS AND CAREER" type="text/html" width="640" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?preview=inline&#038;linkCode=kpd&#038;ref_=k4w_oembed_ZK22PmaN6be7cf&#038;asin=B08HTM7VKY&#038;tag=kpembed-20"></iframe></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/impacts-of-remote-work/">If you are doing this, you are a Naked Emperor in business</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/impacts-of-remote-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does your Business have a Scaffolding?</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/story-of-a-multinational-company/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/story-of-a-multinational-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 12:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/mysterythemes/matina-news/?p=72</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Scaffolding?, For what?&#8221; You must be asking. Yes, like buildings, businesses need scaffoldings that guide them to reach heights. Nicholas K- Quest &#8211; GET SHAP book Imagine...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/story-of-a-multinational-company/">Does your Business have a Scaffolding?</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-center is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"><p><strong> &#8220;Scaffolding?, For what?&#8221;  You must be asking.  Yes, like buildings, businesses need scaffoldings that guide them to reach heights. </strong></p><cite>Nicholas K- Quest &#8211; GET SHAP book</cite></blockquote>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><p>Imagine that you are at home and have to change a light bulb, but you can’t reach the holder in the ceiling. The smart thing to do is get a scaffolding or ladder. But maybe you don’t have a ladder in the house. So you improvise with a stool to elevate your height. But the stool too gets short, so you add a chair on top of it.  You carefully climb on the stool and chair praying that you can maintain your balance long enough to accomplish the task. Unfortunately, you slip and fall. In your next attempt, you seek help for someone to hold the stool and chair for you or for total safety you get a scaffolding. </p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><p>Whereas everyone is smart in business (which we tend to be as entrepreneurs) you cannot tackle all business matters alone, all time. Sometimes you will slip off the stool. And you will need the extra hand for support. This is the scaffolding I am taking about.  It is useful to have a third party’s perspective on matters that require objectivity or an “extra set of eyes/ears” to verify that there are no mistakes made in a critical process and the business growth is gapped with a good scaffolding on an ascending curve other than gambling. </p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><p>Before, in the early cold days of business doing,  it was ok to try and fail until you figured things out. It is now so expensive to be a <em>try-and-see</em> person in such a delicate situation of low resources and jaw biting competition.  From business development strategies, to compliance, contracts and tender processes, legal suits, name it all, you need an external support.  </p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><p>Better to spend UGX 10m on consultancy services and UGX 10m shillings on business set up and development than putting all 20m to risk and burn while drifting.  Business support services like consultancy, accountancy, legal, technological etcetera are key drivers of any business regardless of size and industry.  </p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><p>Arguably, we all know that every new development brings with it changing risks and it becomes good to prevent the risk than curing it. External support service makes this possible; it acts as the scaffolding to change your faulty light bulb.</p> Does your business have a scaffolding?   Learn more <a href="http://www.nbkpremier.com">HERE</a></p>



<p>This article is an extract from the book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GET-SHAP-REIMAGINED-THOUGHTS-BUSINESS/dp/B08HTM7VKY/">GET SHAP </a>.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-amazon wp-block-embed-amazon"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="GET SHAP: REIMAGINED THOUGHTS TO LEVEL UP YOUR BUSINESS AND CAREER" type="text/html" width="640" height="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen style="max-width:100%" src="https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?preview=inline&#038;linkCode=kpd&#038;ref_=k4w_oembed_rSEQomC9WWeiYt&#038;asin=B08HTM7VKY&#038;tag=kpembed-20"></iframe>
</div></figure><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/story-of-a-multinational-company/">Does your Business have a Scaffolding?</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/story-of-a-multinational-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Manage Overtime in Manufacturing &#038; Retail</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/importance-of-strategies-and-planning/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/importance-of-strategies-and-planning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 12:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human Resource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retail and Manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overtime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reatil. manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/mysterythemes/matina-news/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Poor overtime management can cost a business in many ways. Whereas there are a number of things one can implement to improve managing overtime in the workplace,...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/importance-of-strategies-and-planning/">How to Manage Overtime in Manufacturing & Retail</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><em>Poor overtime management can cost a business in many ways. Whereas there are a number of things one can implement to improve managing overtime in the workplace, very few business people (especially in retail and manufacturing) don&#8217;t understand the most effective ways</em></span></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">If you are a manufacturer, retailer or familiar with manufacturing or retail you will agree with me that  it was shelling out for nearly four hours of overtime per week for each employee, or about 500 hours a year.  To standard that was the average for most manufacturers/retailers. </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Overtime is expensive, and not just from a payroll perspective. It can lead to increased product recalls, which also hits your business revenue</span><span style="font-size: 14pt;"> hard.  So, </span><span style="font-size: 14pt; color: initial;">How do you keep your shifts fully functioning without burning out your employees? Or cratering your budget due to out-of-control overtime costs and reduced product quality?</span></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It’s a huge question, but it’s one we can help you answer with something much simpler than you’d imagine. You can cut your overtime costs and improve employee satisfaction with a few simple changes.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><span style="font-size: 24pt;">1. Analyse what’s happening</span> </span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Let me take this opportunity to let you know (unless you didn&#8217;t know) that overtime is one of those things in a business that sneaks up on you until it’s  repeatedly and if taken for granted it can get to a point when its too late to fix. Better management of employee overtime starts by understanding the data behind the overtime problems you have.<strong> &#8220;If you can’t track it, you can’t change it&#8221;.</strong>  I am sure you have never thought about this but it has hit your mind hard now.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Which employees usually take the extra shifts?   How much overtime is being paid out each month? Each quarter? Even yearly? Turn a vague understanding of who’s a hard-working employee into concrete information that can be used for planning.   </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Start by taking a look at your historical data. Look for trends. Have they been increasing? Do you see a seasonal pattern?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You need to track all this early.  Have a tracking system that gives this data often in advance before problems come up. It&#8217;s hard work, so get this information early in advance, package it, sit down and interpret it.  </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Here is an awesome secret;  When such data is easy to access, you have the right foundation for reducing costs at your manufacturing plant or retail store. Knowing the data must come first. You can’t plan if you don’t know. </span></p>
<h2 id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-9" class="comp mntl-sc-block money-sc-block-heading mntl-sc-block-heading"><span class="mntl-sc-block-heading__text" style="font-size: 24pt;">2. Be Proactive</span></h2>
<p id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-11" class="comp text-passage mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-html"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I won&#8217;t spend much time on this. But you well know what proactiveness does.  It applies to overtime management too.  It saves much. It is good anywhere in management and same here. Planning and acting proactively helps companies in avoiding negative impact surprises and helps preparing for the future so as to reduce your expense, protect the company from legal action from disagreements and annoyances of employees, and also improve morale. </span></p>
<p class="comp text-passage mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-html"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Employees are human beings and when proactively informed about overtime schedules they can plan their family time, social life, work life and other important aspects of their living which gives them morale all the time in return. Needless to say more, be a proactive manager or business person that responds in advance instead of reacting to situations already at hand. </span></p>
<h1><span style="font-size: 24pt;">3. Automate </span></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Automation can be a huge help, not just in time saving, but in direct cost saving. </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Simplify your operation schedule and keep employees happy.   Generally, companies distribute overtime based on various work practices, seniority, or union contracts. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This isn’t an easy thing to manage, and a fair distribution of available overtime often ends up relying on a supervisor to write down overtime hours on a piece of paper or plug it into a spreadsheet then distribute it. Sometimes they can forget and distribute it a little late and this hinders employees work plans. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Even worse, for many manufacturing plants, they are obligated to print out and post schedules in break rooms and service shops, making it accessible to all employees. Every time there’s a change, those documents need to be switched out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Relying on a pen and paper or verbal communication is both inconvenient in the time it takes to communicate the information, and also when it comes time to gather that data for use in planning. </span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Automated scheduling would be much better. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 24pt;"><strong>4. Improve Communication </strong></span></p>
<p id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-41" class="comp text-passage mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-html"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">You will agree with me that one of the best ways to effectively manage overtime is to improve communication on schedules, expectations, stakeholders and key principles around it.   Make expectations, schedules and principles clear to employees, managers, facility managers, etc. </span></p>
<p id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-44" class="comp text-passage mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-html"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">There are many unspoken rules about overtime in most companies a reason as to why you will find companies making huge blunders unknowingly. If it is overtime without pay, make it clear.  Because if not clear, no matter how good your employees&#8217; hearts are, wrong expectations eventually affect morale and transparency within the company and takes everything to a negative spiral. </span></p>
<p id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-47" class="comp text-passage mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-html"><span style="font-size: 14pt;">It is very important to clarify your expectations around everything that deals with overtime.  How shall they receive notices, in what time?  From who?   What is their provisions of support? etc. Be clear.  Many companies expect employees to be available to respond to communication any where and anytime, if not well communicated, you may be shocked to find no one responding your calls or email when they didn&#8217;t get better addressing to how communication and when shall be coming in. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong>Conclusion </strong></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Poor overtime management can be a biggest hindrance for most companies. The way any business approaches it defines the difference between avoiding or allowing expensive lawsuits, high labor payment expenses,  low morale, and vulnerability to losing workforce structures. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>NOTE TO PONDER:  </strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><strong>You may need assistance in managing overtime at your store or plant, Contact <a href="http://www.nbkpremier.com">NBK-PREMIER SOLUTIONS LTD</a>, Uganda&#8217;s best business and investment consultancy firm,  to assist you. Contact them <a href="http://www.nbkpremier.com">HERE</a></strong></span></p>
<p> </p>


<p></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/importance-of-strategies-and-planning/">How to Manage Overtime in Manufacturing & Retail</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/importance-of-strategies-and-planning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Automation Drives Innovation</title>
		<link>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/how-automation-drives-innovation/</link>
					<comments>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/how-automation-drives-innovation/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas K. Quest]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AUTOMATION]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[INNOVATION]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LESSONS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/mysterythemes/matina-news/?p=20</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220; VR Equipment. Robots. Blockchain Technolgies. Automated factories. Artificial intelligence. Self-driving cars. Will the machines ultimately take all of our jobs?&#160; What don&#8217;t we see?&#160;&#8221;&#160; &#8211; Nicholas...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/how-automation-drives-innovation/">How Automation Drives Innovation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>&#8220;<span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong><span style="color: #800080;"> VR Equipment. Robots. Blockchain Technolgies. Automated factories. Artificial intelligence. Self-driving cars. Will the machines ultimately take all of our jobs?&nbsp; What don&#8217;t we see?&nbsp;</span>&#8221;&nbsp;</strong></span></p><cite>&#8211; Nicholas K. Quest&#8217;s  reflections  </cite></blockquote></figure>



<p><span style="font-size: 18.6667px;">For those new to the word Automation.&nbsp; According to<a href="https://www.techopedia.com/definition/32099/automation"> Technopedia,</a></span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">&nbsp; automation means the creation and application of technologies to produce and deliver goods and services with minimal human intervention. The implementation of automation technologies, techniques and processes improves the efficiency, reliability, and/or speed of many tasks that were previously performed by humans.&nbsp; Automation is being used in a number of areas such as manufacturing, transport, utilities, defense, facilities, operations and lately, information technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Automation evidently drives innovation.&nbsp; <b>Automation frees up resources</b>, allowing employees to focus their attention on innovation. Automation also helps in improving processes and adopting new ways of working, which can then be automated to help the company become more agile. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">In my quest for knowledge on this topic, I landed on a very interesting story about innovation and automation.&nbsp; It is said, that in 1589, a British Reverend named William Lee invented something called the stocking frame, which was the first machine to automate the knitting industry then, an industry that would consume too much time for housewives and young ladies.&nbsp; Knitting was encouraged by Kings and Queens in a bid that it controlled women to be focused on less distracted to get into earthly pleasures like lust and material exposure. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Reverend William like any other man that thrives form necessity to invent, rumor has it that he invented the machine out of necessity, anyway, call it love… or lust… or whatever you want to call it.&nbsp; It is said that the woman he had a crush on kept using knitting as an excuse not to see him — so he wanted to automate the task and free up her time and be able to have her with no excuse.&nbsp; Take a hint, brother and sister.&nbsp; This trick may help you get more from your other better half.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Away from the concepts behind this automation that led to innovation, William&#8217;s invention and automation ultimately made knitting more efficient, innovative , which did not exactly go over well with most stake holders, out of their ignorance, to the extent that when he applied for a patent for this automated machine, Queen Elizabeth I, through the authorities hesitated to approve. She wanted to protect the country’s knitters and the system in which women were controlled.&nbsp; She didn&#8217;t realize the innovation the machine was to bring to people regardless of losing their hard labor jobs.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">When William&#8217;s&nbsp; first machine that produced a coarse wool, for stocking was refused a patent by <a class="mw-redirect" title="Elizabeth I of England" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_I_of_England">Queen Elizabeth I</a>, he rushed to build another one, an improved one this time, that increased the number of needles per inch from 8 to 20 and produced a silk of finer texture, but the Queen again denied him a patent because of her concern (ignorant and uninformed one possibly) for the employment security of the kingdom&#8217;s many hand knitters whose livelihood might be threatened by such mechanization. That is how deep automation can go. It brings disruption and can build a bad welcome if the innovation it drives is not well put to awareness.&nbsp;</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="font-size: 14pt;">&#8220;Thou aimest high, Master Lee. Consider thou what the invention could do to my poor subjects. It would assuredly bring to them ruin by depriving them of employment, thus making them beggars.&#8221;&nbsp;</span></strong></p>
<p>&#8211; The Queen Responded to William Lee on refusal of patent (in ignorance of the benefits of automation)</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><sup id="cite_ref-AcemogluRobinson2012_5-0" class="reference"></sup>Most likely the Queen’s concern was a manifestation of the hosiers’ guilds&#8217; fear that the invention would make the skills of its artisan members obsolete. <sup id="cite_ref-EB_3-1" class="reference"></sup></span><span style="font-size: 14pt;">William did not give up on his automated invention, he entered into a partnership agreement with a one <a title="George Brooke (conspirator)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Brooke_(conspirator)">George Brooke</a> on 6 June 1600, but the unfortunate Brooke was arrested on an alleged charge of treason and executed in 1603.&nbsp; <sup id="cite_ref-6" class="reference"></sup>Eventually, William moved to France and found better support from some French King then who granted him a patent and the story of automated machines started thereon. Knitting changed and all manner of innovation in the knitting industry spiked until today.</span></p>



<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-9d6595d7 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:100%">
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container is-layout-flow wp-block-group-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Regardless of the resistance and friction (which every new venture gets)<span style="font-size: 14pt;">, William&#8217;s automated machine eventually made its way out into the world, and it did make knitting more efficient and innovative never to look back. A lot of possibilities were created. </span> As humans were driven away from their jobs after automation, they also sought of other ways to innovate and make designs that the  automated machines can take on. They left the hard labor part and focused on what more can the automated machines do for them.</p>
</div></div>
</div>
</div>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Simply analyzed, automation pushed humans to innovate, to get new techniques and developed many more fashion styles with the machine capacities. And to me a great lesson is that, whereas automation shall take away most human jobs, it will also pave more ways of innovation and productivity. </span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I am not saying automation has no bad side of things like rendering humans jobless, but there is an important lesson here, that new things (that we could have been ignorant about, innovation inclusive) come in unexpected ways. With innovation, many effects are evident but we must also appreciate the reality that in the universe there is nothing like total loss, when we lose one thing, we gain another. Because, guess! &#8211; Human capacity is boundless and with automation, innovation is possible more than ever.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">With that regard you may ask, what do we gain from self-driving cars, Virtual reality trends, self service systems, robots, etc.? It is the same, Ask yourself, what can you do with them and the end result shall be total innovation.</span></p>



<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Namaste!</span></p><p>The post <a href="https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/how-automation-drives-innovation/">How Automation Drives Innovation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://thedashafrica.com">theDash Africa</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://thedashafrica.com/2020/08/31/how-automation-drives-innovation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
